<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>BobHarper.org</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.bobharper.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.bobharper.org</link>
	<description>on a quest for authentic spirituality</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 20:03:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.9.9</generator>
	<copyright>2011 </copyright>
	<managingEditor>bob@venturavineyard.org (Bob Harper)</managingEditor>
	<webMaster>bob@venturavineyard.org (Bob Harper)</webMaster>
	<category>Religion &#38; Spirituality: Christianity</category>
	<ttl>1440</ttl>
	<image>
		<url>http://bobharper.org/wp-content/uploads/2009/08/31412_398219973725_541228725_3936263_2507813_n-150x150.jpg</url>
		<title>BobHarper.org</title>
		<link>http://www.bobharper.org</link>
		<width>144</width>
		<height>144</height>
	</image>
	<itunes:subtitle>on a quest for authentic spirituality</itunes:subtitle>
	<itunes:summary>on a quest for authentic spirituality</itunes:summary>
	<itunes:keywords>theology, dispensationalism</itunes:keywords>
	<itunes:category text="Religion &#38; Spirituality">
		<itunes:category text="Christianity" />
	</itunes:category>
	<itunes:author>Bob Harper</itunes:author>
	<itunes:owner>
		<itunes:name>Bob Harper</itunes:name>
		<itunes:email>bob@venturavineyard.org</itunes:email>
	</itunes:owner>
	<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
	<itunes:image href="http://bobharper.org/wp-content/uploads/2009/08/31412_398219973725_541228725_3936263_2507813_n.jpg" />
	<item>
		<title>Revelation 21 and 22</title>
		<link>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/10/25/revelation-21-and-22/</link>
		<comments>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/10/25/revelation-21-and-22/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 20:03:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobharper.org/?p=139</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Chapters 21 &#38; 22: The perspective of John’s first century readers is shaped by two things:  first, persecution and martyrdom are on the way. Its already bad will soon get worse. Second, they are the people of the promise waiting for the Day of the Lord, the decisive moment of salvation and judgment promised by [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chapters 21 &amp; 22: The perspective of John’s first century readers is shaped by two things:  first, persecution and martyrdom are on the way. Its already bad will soon get worse. Second, they are the people of the promise waiting for the Day of the Lord, the decisive moment of salvation and judgment promised by God. In the closing chapters of Revelation John proclaims the Day of the Lord is coming. It will happen. And he reminds his audience that they must remain faithful in the face of persecution to be rewarded on that day.</p>
<p>After heaven and earth flee from the presence of God (20.11) a new heaven and a new earth appear. The first earth, along with the sea (the source of chaos and evil in the ancient world) no longer exists. In the Revelation itself the sea has been portrayed as the origin of cosmic evil (4.6; 12.18; 13.1; 15.2), the nations rebellious to God and who persecute his people (12.18; 13.1), the place of the dead (20.13), the primary location of the world’s idolatrous trade activity (18.10-­‐ 19), as well as literal bodies of water (5.13; 7.1-­‐3; 8.8-­‐9; 10.2, 5-­‐6, 8; 14.7; 16.3).</p>
<p>The new city, the people of God, will exist on this new earth and God will dwell with them on it.  According to G. K. Beale, “This is probably not a portrayal of a literal new creation but a figurative depiction (see on 20.11 and 6.12-­‐15). In light of the qualitative nature of the contrast between ‘new’ creation and ‘first’ creation, it is likely that the meaning of the figurative portrayal is to connote a radically changed cosmos, involving not merely ethical renovation but transformation of the fundamental cosmic structure (including physical elements). Furthermore, ‘there will be no more night’ (22.5; cf. 21.15), which indicates another difference, especially in contrast to Gen. 8.22: ‘While the earth remains&#8230; day and night will not cease.’” In other words the creation will be new or transformed in the same way humans are resurrected. The resurrection body is the transformation of the current body (1 Cor. 15.35-­‐44). The new earth will be transformed from the current one.</p>
<p>John, then, stresses the theme of perseverance from chapters 2 &amp; 3. Those who are victorious, in the face of persecution, will inherit the blessing. “I will be their God and they will be my children.” They will enjoy God’s actual presence and his fulfillment of his promises from chapters 2 and 3 which are: they will eat from the tree of life (2.7); not be hurt by the second death (2.11); be given hidden manna and a white stone (2.17); receive authority over the nations (2.26); not have their names blotted out of the Book of Life (3.5); be a pillar in the temple of God (3.12); sit with Christ on his throne  (3.21).</p>
<p>The same cannot be said for the “cowardly” and “unbelieving.” They will not inherit the blessing and God will not be their God. John is here referring to Christians who do not persevere in the face of persecution.</p>
<p>After that John uses two powerful images to describe the Church in the Day of the Lord.  It is the Bride of Christ (21.9) and the New Jerusalem (21.10-14).  Ezekiel promised an eschatological temple for the people of God.  It turns out that God and the Lamb are that temple (21.22) as well as the source of light (21.23-24).  The city itself is Eden restored (22.1-4).</p>
<p>Then John closes the book with an invitation and a warning (22.12-21): “Look, I am coming soon! My reward is with me, and I will give to each person according to what they have done.”  And, “I warn everyone who hears the words of the prophecy of this scroll: If anyone adds anything to them, God will add to that person the plagues described in this scroll. <strong> </strong>And if anyone takes words away from this scroll of prophecy, God will take away from that person any share in the tree of life and in the Holy City, which are described in this scroll.”  Finally 22.20: “He who testifies to these things says, ‘Yes, I am coming soon.’ Amen. Come, Lord Jesus.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/10/25/revelation-21-and-22/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="http://www.bobharper.org/podpress_trac/feed/139/0/Revelation_21and22.mp3" length="58609536" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>0:30:32</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>Chapters 21 &#38; 22: The perspective of John’s first century readers is shaped by two things:  first, persecution and martyrdom are on the way. Its already bad will soon get worse. Second, they are the people of the promise waiting for the Day of t[...]</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Chapters 21 &#38; 22: The perspective of John’s first century readers is shaped by two things:  first, persecution and martyrdom are on the way. Its already bad will soon get worse. Second, they are the people of the promise waiting for the Day of the Lord, the decisive moment of salvation and judgment promised by God. In the closing chapters of Revelation John proclaims the Day of the Lord is coming. It will happen. And he reminds his audience that they must remain faithful in the face of persecution to be rewarded on that day.
After heaven and earth flee from the presence of God (20.11) a new heaven and a new earth appear. The first earth, along with the sea (the source of chaos and evil in the ancient world) no longer exists. In the Revelation itself the sea has been portrayed as the origin of cosmic evil (4.6; 12.18; 13.1; 15.2), the nations rebellious to God and who persecute his people (12.18; 13.1), the place of the dead (20.13), the primary location of the world’s idolatrous trade activity (18.10-­‐ 19), as well as literal bodies of water (5.13; 7.1-­‐3; 8.8-­‐9; 10.2, 5-­‐6, 8; 14.7; 16.3).
The new city, the people of God, will exist on this new earth and God will dwell with them on it.  According to G. K. Beale, “This is probably not a portrayal of a literal new creation but a figurative depiction (see on 20.11 and 6.12-­‐15). In light of the qualitative nature of the contrast between ‘new’ creation and ‘first’ creation, it is likely that the meaning of the figurative portrayal is to connote a radically changed cosmos, involving not merely ethical renovation but transformation of the fundamental cosmic structure (including physical elements). Furthermore, ‘there will be no more night’ (22.5; cf. 21.15), which indicates another difference, especially in contrast to Gen. 8.22: ‘While the earth remains&#8230; day and night will not cease.’” In other words the creation will be new or transformed in the same way humans are resurrected. The resurrection body is the transformation of the current body (1 Cor. 15.35-­‐44). The new earth will be transformed from the current one.
John, then, stresses the theme of perseverance from chapters 2 &#38; 3. Those who are victorious, in the face of persecution, will inherit the blessing. “I will be their God and they will be my children.” They will enjoy God’s actual presence and his fulfillment of his promises from chapters 2 and 3 which are: they will eat from the tree of life (2.7); not be hurt by the second death (2.11); be given hidden manna and a white stone (2.17); receive authority over the nations (2.26); not have their names blotted out of the Book of Life (3.5); be a pillar in the temple of God (3.12); sit with Christ on his throne  (3.21).
The same cannot be said for the “cowardly” and “unbelieving.” They will not inherit the blessing and God will not be their God. John is here referring to Christians who do not persevere in the face of persecution.
After that John uses two powerful images to describe the Church in the Day of the Lord.  It is the Bride of Christ (21.9) and the New Jerusalem (21.10-14).  Ezekiel promised an eschatological temple for the people of God.  It turns out that God and the Lamb are that temple (21.22) as well as the source of light (21.23-24).  The city itself is Eden restored (22.1-4).
Then John closes the book with an invitation and a warning (22.12-21): “Look, I am coming soon! My reward is with me, and I will give to each person according to what they have done.”  And, “I warn everyone who hears the words of the prophecy of this scroll: If anyone adds anything to them, God will add to that person the plagues described in this scroll.  And if anyone takes words away from this scroll of prophecy, God will take away from that person any share in the tree of life and in the Holy City, which are described in this scroll.”  Finally 22.20: “He who testifies to these things says, ‘Yes, I am coming soon.’ Amen. Come, Lord Jesus.”[...]</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Uncategorized</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bob Harper</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Revelation 20</title>
		<link>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/09/17/revelation-20/</link>
		<comments>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/09/17/revelation-20/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2011 03:35:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bob]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobharper.org/?p=135</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The centerpiece of Revelation 20 is the millennium.  It’s hard to imagine a doctrine or place in the Bible more disputed than the millennium.  What the heck is it?  There are three basic options, each with variations: 1. Premillennialism: a literal reading of the passage in which Jesus returns and established God’s kingdom for a literal [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The centerpiece of Revelation 20 is the millennium.  It’s hard to imagine a doctrine or place in the Bible more disputed than the millennium.  What the heck is it?  There are three basic options, each with variations: 1<span style="text-decoration: underline;">. <strong><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: 10px; line-height: 19px;">Premillennialism: a literal reading of the passage in which Jesus returns and established God’s kingdom for a literal 1000 year period. </span></strong></span>This is the newest viewpoint and the most popular in North America.  According to Craig Blaising premillennialists “believe that when Jesus comes. He will raise the dead in two stages.  First, he will raise some to participate with him in the millennial kingdom.  After the Millennium (the thousand-year period) is over, he will raise the rest of the dead and institute the Final Judgment.  Then will come the final and eternal destinies of the saved and the lost.”</p>
<p>The problems with this view are:</p>
<p><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: 10px; line-height: 19px;">1. You must now read the entire revelation “literally” something no one actually does.</span></p>
<p><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: 10px; line-height: 19px;">2. The Old Testament says nothing about a thousand-year reign.  Instead it points to the Day of the Lord, a decisive day of judgment and salvation.  This would be the only major image in Revelation not drawn from the Old Testament.</span></p>
<ol>
<li>3. The “thousand” in this passage becomes the only completely literal number in the Revelation.  According to Darrell Johnson, ““<em>The one thousand years is not a statistic.  It is a symbol.</em>  The millennial reign could turn out to be exactly one thousand years.  But that is not what John is saying… in the last book of the Bible… all numbers have turned out to be symbols, not statistics.”</li>
</ol>
<p>2. <span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: 10px; line-height: 19px;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Postmillennialism: this view interprets the thousand years symbolically and teaches that Jesus will return after the church dominates the world and establishes a golden period.</span></span></p>
<p>Kenneth Gentry writes, “Postmillennialism expects the proclaiming of the Spirit-blessed gospel of Jesus Christ to win the vast majority of human beings to salvation in the present age. Increasing gospel success will gradually produce a time in history prior to Christ’s return in which faith, righteousness, peace, and prosperity will prevail in the affairs of people and of nations. After an extensive era of such conditions the Lord will return visibly, bodily, and in great glory, ending history with the general resurrection and the great judgment of all humankind.”  In other words the church will bring about an age of righteousness that will immediately precede Jesus’ return.</p>
<p>Gentry adds, “Postmillennialists emphasize the covenantal crushing of Satan in history at Christ’s first advent, with its results being progressively worked out in history on the plane of Adam’s original rebellion, Satan’s consequent struggle, and Christ’s incarnational intrusion. “</p>
<p>An adaptation of postmillennialism called “theonomic postmillennialism” is currently growing in popularity.  According to this view the church will influence a gradual return to the Mosaic Law though evangelism and discipleship.</p>
<p>The biggest problem with this view is history, which doesn’t bear it out at all.  The church is not gaining control of the world and reforming it “for Jesus.”</p>
<p>3. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Amillennialism: The millennium is not a literal 1000-year reign but reflects the </span>                <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Bible’s now and not yet tension.</span></p>
<ul>
<li>Currently all authority belongs to Jesus (Matt. 28.18) but the fullness of that is yet to come.  Amillennialists believe that all things will conclude with Jesus second return.</li>
<li>Amillennialists see the promises made in the Old Testament of a righteous kingdom and glorious temple fulfilled in the church.  Robert Strimple writes, “With regard to the New Testament revelation concerning the future, however, we must say even more than that. Not only does the New Testament not teach a future millennial kingdom, in what it teaches us about Christ’s second coming, the New Testament rules out an earthly millennial kingdom following Christ’s return, because the New Testament reveals clearly that the following events are all concurrent; that is, all will occur together in one cluster of end-time events, one grand dramatic finale of redemptive history: the second coming of Christ, the resurrection of believers (and the “change” of living believers, 1 Cor. 15:51), the resurrection of the unjust, judgment for all, the end, the new heaven and new earth, and the inauguration of the final kingdom of God, the blessed eternal state of the redeemed. “</li>
<li>Also amillennialists draw on several NT verses that seem to teach one resurrection and one judgment (John 5.28-29; 2 Thessalonians 1.5-10; Rom. 8.17-33; 2 Peter 3.3-14; 1 Cor. 15.20-26)</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Then what is the millennium described in Chapter 20?</strong></p>
<p><strong></strong><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: 10px; line-height: 19px;">The millennium is an image describing the role of the saints in the kingdom now before the final judgment.  It is one more angle or perspective on the events of the previous few chapters.  </span><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: 10px; line-height: 19px;">According to Robert Strimple, “…Revelation 20:1-10 is a figurative representation of Christ’s victory over Satan at each of the two climactic points. At the cross Satan is bound—but not absolutely. Revelation 20:2-3 does not say that Satan is bound, period. He is bound in one respect only, namely, “to keep him from deceiving the nations [the Gentiles] anymore.” The age of salvation for the Gentiles has arrived. Prior to Christ’s ministry Israel was the one nation called out from all the nations of the world to know God’s blessings and to serve him. There were exceptions, of  course—those who came to know God’s grace even though they were not of the children of Abraham after the flesh. But essentially all the nations on this earth were in darkness, under Satan’s deception. But then, praise God! Christ came and accomplished his redemptive work. On the day of Pentecost the Holy Spirit was poured out “on all people” (Acts 2:17), signifying the fact that the gospel of Christ is a gospel for all the nations, not just the Jewish people. The age of world missions had begun, and Satan’s deceptive work on that grand scale over so many centuries had come to an end.”</span></p>
<ul>
<li>So the millennium is the age in which the Gospel goes forth to all people.  This is how the saints “rule.”</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/09/17/revelation-20/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="http://www.bobharper.org/podpress_trac/feed/135/0/Revelation_20.mp3" length="69154944" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>0:36:01</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>The centerpiece of Revelation 20 is the millennium.  It’s hard to imagine a doctrine or place in the Bible more disputed than the millennium.  What the heck is it?  There are three basic options, each with variations: 1. Premillennialism: a literal [...]</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>The centerpiece of Revelation 20 is the millennium.  It’s hard to imagine a doctrine or place in the Bible more disputed than the millennium.  What the heck is it?  There are three basic options, each with variations: 1. Premillennialism: a literal reading of the passage in which Jesus returns and established God’s kingdom for a literal 1000 year period. This is the newest viewpoint and the most popular in North America.  According to Craig Blaising premillennialists “believe that when Jesus comes. He will raise the dead in two stages.  First, he will raise some to participate with him in the millennial kingdom.  After the Millennium (the thousand-year period) is over, he will raise the rest of the dead and institute the Final Judgment.  Then will come the final and eternal destinies of the saved and the lost.”
The problems with this view are:
1. You must now read the entire revelation “literally” something no one actually does.
2. The Old Testament says nothing about a thousand-year reign.  Instead it points to the Day of the Lord, a decisive day of judgment and salvation.  This would be the only major image in Revelation not drawn from the Old Testament.

3. The “thousand” in this passage becomes the only completely literal number in the Revelation.  According to Darrell Johnson, ““The one thousand years is not a statistic.  It is a symbol.  The millennial reign could turn out to be exactly one thousand years.  But that is not what John is saying… in the last book of the Bible… all numbers have turned out to be symbols, not statistics.”

2. Postmillennialism: this view interprets the thousand years symbolically and teaches that Jesus will return after the church dominates the world and establishes a golden period.
Kenneth Gentry writes, “Postmillennialism expects the proclaiming of the Spirit-blessed gospel of Jesus Christ to win the vast majority of human beings to salvation in the present age. Increasing gospel success will gradually produce a time in history prior to Christ’s return in which faith, righteousness, peace, and prosperity will prevail in the affairs of people and of nations. After an extensive era of such conditions the Lord will return visibly, bodily, and in great glory, ending history with the general resurrection and the great judgment of all humankind.”  In other words the church will bring about an age of righteousness that will immediately precede Jesus’ return.
Gentry adds, “Postmillennialists emphasize the covenantal crushing of Satan in history at Christ’s first advent, with its results being progressively worked out in history on the plane of Adam’s original rebellion, Satan’s consequent struggle, and Christ’s incarnational intrusion. “
An adaptation of postmillennialism called “theonomic postmillennialism” is currently growing in popularity.  According to this view the church will influence a gradual return to the Mosaic Law though evangelism and discipleship.
The biggest problem with this view is history, which doesn’t bear it out at all.  The church is not gaining control of the world and reforming it “for Jesus.”
3. Amillennialism: The millennium is not a literal 1000-year reign but reflects the                 Bible’s now and not yet tension.

Currently all authority belongs to Jesus (Matt. 28.18) but the fullness of that is yet to come.  Amillennialists believe that all things will conclude with Jesus second return.
Amillennialists see the promises made in the Old Testament of a righteous kingdom and glorious temple fulfilled in the church.  Robert Strimple writes, “With regard to the New Testament revelation concerning the future, however, we must say even more than that. Not only does the New Testament not teach a future millennial kingdom, in what it teaches us about Christ’s second coming, the New Testament rules out an earthly millennial kingdom following Christ’s return, because the New Testament reveals clearly that the following events are all concurrent; that is, all will occur [...]</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Uncategorized</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bob Harper</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Revelation 19</title>
		<link>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/09/17/revelation-19/</link>
		<comments>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/09/17/revelation-19/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2011 03:22:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bob]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobharper.org/?p=133</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Two major events occur simultaneously in this chapter: the wedding of the Lamb and His bride and the overthrow of the false trinity.  The images in it draw heavily on Jewish wedding customs and the triumph of the victorious Roman General.  Both images are mixed.  The Bride “has made herself ready” and her bridegroom comes [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two major events occur simultaneously in this chapter: the wedding of the Lamb and His bride and the overthrow of the false trinity.  The images in it draw heavily on Jewish wedding customs and the triumph of the victorious Roman General.  Both images are mixed.  The Bride “has made herself ready” and her bridegroom comes for her.  This is the Second Coming, the marriage feast of the Lamb.  There were three steps to take in getting married in first century Judaism.  <strong>Step one</strong> was the betrothal or engagement.  The groom would leave his father’s house and go negotiate the bride price with her father.  As soon as he paid that price the marriage went into effect.  The man and the woman are legally married at this point even though the union has not been consummated.  She would be declared “consecrated” or “set apart” for her husband.  They then drank a glass of wine together to establish their new covenant.  The words of blessing, “this cup is the new covenant,” would be spoken over it.  Then the groom would leave and go back to his father’s house for roughly 12 months.  <strong>Step two</strong> was the preparation for the wedding. During this year of separation the groom would prepare a room for his bride and she would prepare herself for the wedding.  It is important to know that they are legally married even though they don’t see each other, live together, or have even consecrated the marriage.  If the man dies during this period the woman is considered a widow.  <strong>Step three</strong> was the wedding itself.  The bridegroom would leave his home at an unknown hour dressed for the wedding with best man and friends.   Part of the idea was to surprise the bride and her attendants.  When he got close his groomsmen would shout, “Here is the bridegroom!  Come out.  Come out to meet him.”  Then the bride and her attendants would come out carrying lamps to join the party.  They would go back to the groom’s father’s house where they would find the guests dressed in special robes.  The feast and party could last 14 days.  The time of the church&#8217;s engagement has passed.  Babylon has been judged.  Salvation arrives with Jesus.  But he is not only a bridegroom; he is also a warrior in John’s vision.  The armies of heaven ride with him against the beast and his armies.   They are defeated without a battle because the Messiah brings the word of God against them.  John draws on the Roman triumph for his imagery of Jesus.  A Roman general who won a great victory could be awarded a “Triumph” by the Senate.  This was a party that began with a parade.  The general, dressed in white, and his army would enter Rome through a special white arch to cleanse them from their bloodshed.  this is the promised Day of the Lord, salvation is at hand.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/09/17/revelation-19/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="http://www.bobharper.org/podpress_trac/feed/133/0/Revelation_19.mp3" length="47357568" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>0:24:40</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>Two major events occur simultaneously in this chapter: the wedding of the Lamb and His bride and the overthrow of the false trinity.  The images in it draw heavily on Jewish wedding customs and the triumph of the victorious Roman General.  Both imag[...]</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Two major events occur simultaneously in this chapter: the wedding of the Lamb and His bride and the overthrow of the false trinity.  The images in it draw heavily on Jewish wedding customs and the triumph of the victorious Roman General.  Both images are mixed.  The Bride “has made herself ready” and her bridegroom comes for her.  This is the Second Coming, the marriage feast of the Lamb.  There were three steps to take in getting married in first century Judaism.  Step one was the betrothal or engagement.  The groom would leave his father’s house and go negotiate the bride price with her father.  As soon as he paid that price the marriage went into effect.  The man and the woman are legally married at this point even though the union has not been consummated.  She would be declared “consecrated” or “set apart” for her husband.  They then drank a glass of wine together to establish their new covenant.  The words of blessing, “this cup is the new covenant,” would be spoken over it.  Then the groom would leave and go back to his father’s house for roughly 12 months.  Step two was the preparation for the wedding. During this year of separation the groom would prepare a room for his bride and she would prepare herself for the wedding.  It is important to know that they are legally married even though they don’t see each other, live together, or have even consecrated the marriage.  If the man dies during this period the woman is considered a widow.  Step three was the wedding itself.  The bridegroom would leave his home at an unknown hour dressed for the wedding with best man and friends.   Part of the idea was to surprise the bride and her attendants.  When he got close his groomsmen would shout, “Here is the bridegroom!  Come out.  Come out to meet him.”  Then the bride and her attendants would come out carrying lamps to join the party.  They would go back to the groom’s father’s house where they would find the guests dressed in special robes.  The feast and party could last 14 days.  The time of the church&#8217;s engagement has passed.  Babylon has been judged.  Salvation arrives with Jesus.  But he is not only a bridegroom; he is also a warrior in John’s vision.  The armies of heaven ride with him against the beast and his armies.   They are defeated without a battle because the Messiah brings the word of God against them.  John draws on the Roman triumph for his imagery of Jesus.  A Roman general who won a great victory could be awarded a “Triumph” by the Senate.  This was a party that began with a parade.  The general, dressed in white, and his army would enter Rome through a special white arch to cleanse them from their bloodshed.  this is the promised Day of the Lord, salvation is at hand.</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Uncategorized</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bob Harper</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Revelation 17 and 18</title>
		<link>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/08/24/revelation-17-and-18/</link>
		<comments>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/08/24/revelation-17-and-18/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 22:41:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bob]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobharper.org/?p=128</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Now John is directed toward the judgment of God on Rome itself.  He sees a woman riding a beast.  The image is probably drawn from one of the goddess &#8220;Roma&#8221; popular on coins of the time.  The woman is covered with blasphemous names.  These are titles of self-deification rather than slanders against God.  The woman [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Now John is directed toward the judgment of God on Rome itself.  He sees a woman riding a beast.  The image is probably drawn from one of the goddess &#8220;Roma&#8221; popular on coins of the time.  The woman is covered with blasphemous names.  These are titles of self-deification rather than slanders against God.  The woman is drunk from the blood of the saints whom she has persecuted and killed.  The beast she is sitting on has seven heads and ten horns.  The angel tells John the seven heads are seven hills and seven kings.  Who are the kings?  Many commentators believe this is a reference to specific Roman emperors.  The problem with that is there were more than seven emperors by the time Revelation was written.  So people typically find a creative way to count them to come up with Domitian being the sixth emperor, the seventh yet to come.  You can hear the most common of the various options on the audio file.   It is more likely the heads represent anti-Christian despots in general.  It turns out the ten horns are also ten kings.   This image likely corresponds to the Roman governors, very powerful local rulers (think Herod the Great) who served under the emperor and pledged allegiance to him.   John&#8217;s larger point is the beast and the prostitute are highly organized but defeated by the Lamb, who was slain.  This would reinforce to John&#8217;s first readers that God&#8217;s people overcome through weakness and suffering.  After this chapter 18 follows with an elegant piece of poetry lamenting the destruction of the prostitute.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/08/24/revelation-17-and-18/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="http://www.bobharper.org/podpress_trac/feed/128/0/Revelation_17and18.mp3" length="65429376" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>0:34:05</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>Now John is directed toward the judgment of God on Rome itself.  He sees a woman riding a beast.  The image is probably drawn from one of the goddess &#8220;Roma&#8221; popular on coins of the time.  The woman is covered with blasphemous names.  The[...]</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Now John is directed toward the judgment of God on Rome itself.  He sees a woman riding a beast.  The image is probably drawn from one of the goddess &#8220;Roma&#8221; popular on coins of the time.  The woman is covered with blasphemous names.  These are titles of self-deification rather than slanders against God.  The woman is drunk from the blood of the saints whom she has persecuted and killed.  The beast she is sitting on has seven heads and ten horns.  The angel tells John the seven heads are seven hills and seven kings.  Who are the kings?  Many commentators believe this is a reference to specific Roman emperors.  The problem with that is there were more than seven emperors by the time Revelation was written.  So people typically find a creative way to count them to come up with Domitian being the sixth emperor, the seventh yet to come.  You can hear the most common of the various options on the audio file.   It is more likely the heads represent anti-Christian despots in general.  It turns out the ten horns are also ten kings.   This image likely corresponds to the Roman governors, very powerful local rulers (think Herod the Great) who served under the emperor and pledged allegiance to him.   John&#8217;s larger point is the beast and the prostitute are highly organized but defeated by the Lamb, who was slain.  This would reinforce to John&#8217;s first readers that God&#8217;s people overcome through weakness and suffering.  After this chapter 18 follows with an elegant piece of poetry lamenting the destruction of the prostitute.</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Uncategorized</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bob Harper</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Revelation 15 &amp; 16</title>
		<link>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/08/08/revelation-15-16/</link>
		<comments>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/08/08/revelation-15-16/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 13:41:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bob]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobharper.org/?p=120</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[These two chapters detail God’s awesome judgment, the “grape harvest” of chapter 14.  Seven angels are prepared with bowls containing the seven final plagues, “with them the wrath of God is completed.”  As they leave the heavenly temple it is filled with smoke just as the earthly tabernacle and Solomon’s temple were at their consecration.   [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>These two chapters detail God’s awesome judgment, the “grape harvest” of chapter 14.  Seven angels are prepared with bowls containing the seven final plagues, “with them the wrath of God is completed.”  As they leave the heavenly temple it is filled with smoke just as the earthly tabernacle and Solomon’s temple were at their consecration.   The bowls of judgment are poured our in rapid succession.  There is no more opportunity for salvation.  The offer is revoked.  There is one thing important to keep in mind when reading this chapter.   We read it from a place of power, as individuals, in an age that seeks “fairness.”  In a very real way our lives are positively intertwined with the powers of this age (i.e., political, economic, social, etc).  Consequently the talk of God’s wrath is difficult for us.  The early Christians lived in a very different world.  They were powerless with no expectation that this would change.  The world around them was obviously unfair.  Those with power exploited it to their benefit.  That’s what everyone expected.  The Christians themselves expected to suffer in such a world.  Therefore they read these judgments with joy understanding not just that their suffering was over but that the age itself is closing so that the reign of God can begin.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/08/08/revelation-15-16/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="http://www.bobharper.org/podpress_trac/feed/120/0/Revelation_15and16.mp3" length="52232832" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>0:27:12</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>These two chapters detail God’s awesome judgment, the “grape harvest” of chapter 14.  Seven angels are prepared with bowls containing the seven final plagues, “with them the wrath of God is completed.”  As they leave the heavenly temple it is filled[...]</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>These two chapters detail God’s awesome judgment, the “grape harvest” of chapter 14.  Seven angels are prepared with bowls containing the seven final plagues, “with them the wrath of God is completed.”  As they leave the heavenly temple it is filled with smoke just as the earthly tabernacle and Solomon’s temple were at their consecration.   The bowls of judgment are poured our in rapid succession.  There is no more opportunity for salvation.  The offer is revoked.  There is one thing important to keep in mind when reading this chapter.   We read it from a place of power, as individuals, in an age that seeks “fairness.”  In a very real way our lives are positively intertwined with the powers of this age (i.e., political, economic, social, etc).  Consequently the talk of God’s wrath is difficult for us.  The early Christians lived in a very different world.  They were powerless with no expectation that this would change.  The world around them was obviously unfair.  Those with power exploited it to their benefit.  That’s what everyone expected.  The Christians themselves expected to suffer in such a world.  Therefore they read these judgments with joy understanding not just that their suffering was over but that the age itself is closing so that the reign of God can begin.</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Uncategorized</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bob Harper</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Revelation 14</title>
		<link>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/08/08/revelation-14/</link>
		<comments>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/08/08/revelation-14/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 13:40:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bob]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobharper.org/?p=118</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[God now rewards the loyalty of the saints, which has at times cost them their life.  In Revelation 14 John begins the prophetic cycle of God’s ultimate judgment and victory.  As it opens the opposing forces are prepared for conflict.  The Lamb stands on Mount Zion with the 144,000, the ideal number of the redeemed.  [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>God now rewards the loyalty of the saints, which has at times cost them their life.  In Revelation 14 John begins the prophetic cycle of God’s ultimate judgment and victory.  As it opens the opposing forces are prepared for conflict.  The Lamb stands on Mount Zion with the 144,000, the ideal number of the redeemed.  Three angels fly in midair each with a distinctive message.  One proclaims the Gospel, one last chance for the human allies of the false trinity: the beast, dragon, and false prophet to change sides.  The second angel proclaims the destruction of Babylon (or Rome), which will be detailed in chapters 17 and 18.  It makes sense for the earthly representative of the false trinity to be judged and defeated along with it.  The third angel proclaims that those who align with Babylon will be judged with her.  The chapter closes with two great harvests on the earth.  In the first, based on the grain harvest, the redeemed from all nations are collected and offered to God as the first fruits of all nations.  The second harvest is patterned after the grape harvest.  It is the harvest of God’s wrath and judgment upon those who worshipped the beast.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/08/08/revelation-14/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="http://www.bobharper.org/podpress_trac/feed/118/0/Revelation_14.mp3" length="65076864" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>0:33:54</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>God now rewards the loyalty of the saints, which has at times cost them their life.  In Revelation 14 John begins the prophetic cycle of God’s ultimate judgment and victory.  As it opens the opposing forces are prepared for conflict.  The Lamb stand[...]</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>God now rewards the loyalty of the saints, which has at times cost them their life.  In Revelation 14 John begins the prophetic cycle of God’s ultimate judgment and victory.  As it opens the opposing forces are prepared for conflict.  The Lamb stands on Mount Zion with the 144,000, the ideal number of the redeemed.  Three angels fly in midair each with a distinctive message.  One proclaims the Gospel, one last chance for the human allies of the false trinity: the beast, dragon, and false prophet to change sides.  The second angel proclaims the destruction of Babylon (or Rome), which will be detailed in chapters 17 and 18.  It makes sense for the earthly representative of the false trinity to be judged and defeated along with it.  The third angel proclaims that those who align with Babylon will be judged with her.  The chapter closes with two great harvests on the earth.  In the first, based on the grain harvest, the redeemed from all nations are collected and offered to God as the first fruits of all nations.  The second harvest is patterned after the grape harvest.  It is the harvest of God’s wrath and judgment upon those who worshipped the beast.</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Uncategorized</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bob Harper</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Revelation 13</title>
		<link>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/06/25/revelation-13/</link>
		<comments>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/06/25/revelation-13/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 05:19:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bob]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobharper.org/?p=112</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There are few figures in literature more compelling than the “antichrist” or the beast of Revelation 13.  For dispensationalists he is the world leader who will emerge from the European Union.   The list of people nominated for the job is impressive including Adolf Hitler, Josef Stalin, Ronald Reagan, Mikhail Gorbachev and more.   In this chapter [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There are few figures in literature more compelling than the “antichrist” or the beast of Revelation 13.  For dispensationalists he is the world leader who will emerge from the European Union.   The list of people nominated for the job is impressive including Adolf Hitler, Josef Stalin, Ronald Reagan, Mikhail Gorbachev and more.   In this chapter John is actually bringing a long tradition that goes back to Second Temple Judaism to a fresh and final point.   In that early period there was an expectation that two oppressors would arise against Israel: one from without who would have political power and one from within who would deceive through false teaching.  Antiochus IV (Epiphanes) is the actual model for this.  He is the Greek ruler who tried to outlaw Judaism and sparked the Macabbean revolt instead.  Jesus refers to him in the Olivet Discourse.   Although I argue that the Olivet Discourse is fulfilled, Jesus reference shows the power of the story of Antiochus even in the early church.  Writing in the mid 50s, Paul talks about a “man of lawlessness” in 2 Thessalonians 2.  This person rises from within the church and is destroyed at Jesus second coming.  In 1 and 2 John the concept of the antichrist is widened to include anyone who denies the Father and the Son or denies that Jesus came in the flesh.   The beast in Revelation 13 represents the culmination of this tradition shaped by the fear of Caesar Nero.  His mark is the counterpoint to the sealing of God’s servants.  Without a doubt he will make life difficult for the people of God.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/06/25/revelation-13/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="http://www.bobharper.org/podpress_trac/feed/112/0/Revelation_13.mp3" length="76224384" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>0:39:42</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>There are few figures in literature more compelling than the “antichrist” or the beast of Revelation 13.  For dispensationalists he is the world leader who will emerge from the European Union.   The list of people nominated for the job is impressive[...]</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>There are few figures in literature more compelling than the “antichrist” or the beast of Revelation 13.  For dispensationalists he is the world leader who will emerge from the European Union.   The list of people nominated for the job is impressive including Adolf Hitler, Josef Stalin, Ronald Reagan, Mikhail Gorbachev and more.   In this chapter John is actually bringing a long tradition that goes back to Second Temple Judaism to a fresh and final point.   In that early period there was an expectation that two oppressors would arise against Israel: one from without who would have political power and one from within who would deceive through false teaching.  Antiochus IV (Epiphanes) is the actual model for this.  He is the Greek ruler who tried to outlaw Judaism and sparked the Macabbean revolt instead.  Jesus refers to him in the Olivet Discourse.   Although I argue that the Olivet Discourse is fulfilled, Jesus reference shows the power of the story of Antiochus even in the early church.  Writing in the mid 50s, Paul talks about a “man of lawlessness” in 2 Thessalonians 2.  This person rises from within the church and is destroyed at Jesus second coming.  In 1 and 2 John the concept of the antichrist is widened to include anyone who denies the Father and the Son or denies that Jesus came in the flesh.   The beast in Revelation 13 represents the culmination of this tradition shaped by the fear of Caesar Nero.  His mark is the counterpoint to the sealing of God’s servants.  Without a doubt he will make life difficult for the people of God.
&#160;</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Uncategorized</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bob Harper</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Revelation 12</title>
		<link>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/06/25/revelation-12/</link>
		<comments>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/06/25/revelation-12/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 05:18:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bob]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobharper.org/?p=110</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In this chapter John sees a vision of a woman “clothed with the sun and the moon under her feet” in labor and ready to give birth.  She represents the purified people of God and is a counterpoint to the prostitute on the beast in chapters 17 &#38; 18.  She gives birth to a male [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In this chapter John sees a vision of a woman “clothed with the sun and the moon under her feet” in labor and ready to give birth.  She represents the purified people of God and is a counterpoint to the prostitute on the beast in chapters 17 &amp; 18.  She gives birth to a male child who is Christ.  A dragon prowls before her anxious to devour her child.  Before that can happen the child is snatched up to heaven.  The woman is then hidden in the wilderness.  This does not stop the dragon from pursuing her.  He is cast down to earth, or restricted, and is even more murderous than usual because of it.  In this chapter, as well as the next several, the same scene is portrayed from different angles.  The basics are the same: an indeterminate time of trouble and testing is to ensue, the church will be persecuted during this time, Satan will seem to gain the upper hand, but Jesus will return and God will vindicate His people.   Over the next eight chapters that set of events will be given to us from God’s point of view, the church’s point of view, etc.   The main point of John’s prophecy is the end is coming.  As verse 10 says, “Now have come the salvation and the power and the kingdom of our God, and the authority of his Messiah.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/06/25/revelation-12/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="http://www.bobharper.org/podpress_trac/feed/110/0/Revelation_12.mp3" length="70003464" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>0:36:28</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>In this chapter John sees a vision of a woman “clothed with the sun and the moon under her feet” in labor and ready to give birth.  She represents the purified people of God and is a counterpoint to the prostitute on the beast in chapters 17 &#38; 1[...]</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>In this chapter John sees a vision of a woman “clothed with the sun and the moon under her feet” in labor and ready to give birth.  She represents the purified people of God and is a counterpoint to the prostitute on the beast in chapters 17 &#38; 18.  She gives birth to a male child who is Christ.  A dragon prowls before her anxious to devour her child.  Before that can happen the child is snatched up to heaven.  The woman is then hidden in the wilderness.  This does not stop the dragon from pursuing her.  He is cast down to earth, or restricted, and is even more murderous than usual because of it.  In this chapter, as well as the next several, the same scene is portrayed from different angles.  The basics are the same: an indeterminate time of trouble and testing is to ensue, the church will be persecuted during this time, Satan will seem to gain the upper hand, but Jesus will return and God will vindicate His people.   Over the next eight chapters that set of events will be given to us from God’s point of view, the church’s point of view, etc.   The main point of John’s prophecy is the end is coming.  As verse 10 says, “Now have come the salvation and the power and the kingdom of our God, and the authority of his Messiah.”</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Uncategorized</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bob Harper</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Revelation 11</title>
		<link>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/06/01/revelation-11/</link>
		<comments>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/06/01/revelation-11/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 13:03:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bob]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobharper.org/?p=106</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Chapter eleven of the Book of Revelation is the beginning of John’s ministry after his recommissioning.  Although the narrative will still loop from future to past to present and back again, from here on the primary message is about the ultimate end.  John is told to measure “the temple, its altar, with its worshippers” in [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chapter eleven of the Book of Revelation is the beginning of John’s ministry after his recommissioning.  Although the narrative will still loop from future to past to present and back again, from here on the primary message is about the ultimate end.  John is told to measure “the temple, its altar, with its worshippers” in Revelation 11.   What temple?  There are four options.  The first is God’s heavenly temple.  Almost no one believes that temple is what John is referring to.  The second is Herod’s Temple.   Full Preterists (those who believe the entire Book of Revelation was fulfilled by 70 AD) believe that is the temple John is referring to.  Dispensationalists believe the temple will be rebuilt in Jerusalem before the end comes and animal sacrifice will be practiced there.   The best option is that the temple in Revelation 11 is the church (1 Cor 3.16-17; 6.19; 2 Cor 6.16; Eph. 2.21; I Pet. 2.5).  In fact this is one of several images of the church triumphing in the midst of trouble which John will use over the next few chapters.  The church’s ministry is similar to that of Moses and Elijah.   The beast will be able to kill the church after she finishes her testimony.   Suddenly, though, God will bring life back to the church.  “At that very hour a severe earthquake” hits and shortly after that the seventh and final trumpet sounds announcing that the Kingdom has come to earth.   Although Revelation announces the “End” here the book has many more things to say in the remaining eleven chapters.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/06/01/revelation-11/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="http://www.bobharper.org/podpress_trac/feed/106/0/Revelation_11.mp3" length="41109975" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>0:42:49</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>Chapter eleven of the Book of Revelation is the beginning of John’s ministry after his recommissioning.  Although the narrative will still loop from future to past to present and back again, from here on the primary message is about the ultimate end[...]</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Chapter eleven of the Book of Revelation is the beginning of John’s ministry after his recommissioning.  Although the narrative will still loop from future to past to present and back again, from here on the primary message is about the ultimate end.  John is told to measure “the temple, its altar, with its worshippers” in Revelation 11.   What temple?  There are four options.  The first is God’s heavenly temple.  Almost no one believes that temple is what John is referring to.  The second is Herod’s Temple.   Full Preterists (those who believe the entire Book of Revelation was fulfilled by 70 AD) believe that is the temple John is referring to.  Dispensationalists believe the temple will be rebuilt in Jerusalem before the end comes and animal sacrifice will be practiced there.   The best option is that the temple in Revelation 11 is the church (1 Cor 3.16-17; 6.19; 2 Cor 6.16; Eph. 2.21; I Pet. 2.5).  In fact this is one of several images of the church triumphing in the midst of trouble which John will use over the next few chapters.  The church’s ministry is similar to that of Moses and Elijah.   The beast will be able to kill the church after she finishes her testimony.   Suddenly, though, God will bring life back to the church.  “At that very hour a severe earthquake” hits and shortly after that the seventh and final trumpet sounds announcing that the Kingdom has come to earth.   Although Revelation announces the “End” here the book has many more things to say in the remaining eleven chapters.
&#160;</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Uncategorized</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bob Harper</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Revelation 10</title>
		<link>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/05/27/revelation-10/</link>
		<comments>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/05/27/revelation-10/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2011 01:13:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bob]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobharper.org/?p=100</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Revelation chapter 10 is an important dividing line for understanding the entire book.  Richard Bauckham makes this point, “It is not until chapter 10 that the main content of the prophetic revelation John communicates in his book is given to him.  All that has preceded is preparatory – necessary to the understanding of this revelation, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Revelation chapter 10 is an important dividing line for understanding the entire book.  Richard Bauckham makes this point, “It is not until chapter 10 that the main content of the prophetic revelation John communicates in his book is given to him.  All that has preceded is preparatory – necessary to the understanding of this revelation, but not itself the revelation.  Recognizing this is a vital, though neglected, key to understanding the Book of Revelation.” In the previous nine chapters John’s visions portray life as it is and will be throughout this Age.  This Age is marked by “wars and rumors of wars and earthquakes in various places.”  It is also marked by the extended hand of God bringing judgment designed to bring people to repentance.  By 9.21, though, it is obvious that humanity is not heeding God’s call to repent.  So instead of offering the thunder judgments as one more opportunity to repent God decides to move toward the final judgment.   John encounters Jesus as a mighty angel (see Exod. 3.2-12; Jud. 6.22; 2 Kgs. 1.3-15; 1 Chron. 21.18 for preincarnate references to Jesus as the angel of the lord).   The angel swears that the time has come for the seventh (and last) trumpet to be sounded and for the mystery of God to be completed.  He recommissions John to take now a message of God’s judgment.  He offers John the scroll to eat.  It is sweet to taste but bitter to eat.  This means the coming salvation for believers and judgment on this age will involve more suffering and persecution for Christians.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/05/27/revelation-10/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="http://www.bobharper.org/podpress_trac/feed/100/0/Revelation10.mp3" length="24946010" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>0:25:59</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>Revelation chapter 10 is an important dividing line for understanding the entire book.  Richard Bauckham makes this point, “It is not until chapter 10 that the main content of the prophetic revelation John communicates in his book is given to him.  [...]</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Revelation chapter 10 is an important dividing line for understanding the entire book.  Richard Bauckham makes this point, “It is not until chapter 10 that the main content of the prophetic revelation John communicates in his book is given to him.  All that has preceded is preparatory – necessary to the understanding of this revelation, but not itself the revelation.  Recognizing this is a vital, though neglected, key to understanding the Book of Revelation.” In the previous nine chapters John’s visions portray life as it is and will be throughout this Age.  This Age is marked by “wars and rumors of wars and earthquakes in various places.”  It is also marked by the extended hand of God bringing judgment designed to bring people to repentance.  By 9.21, though, it is obvious that humanity is not heeding God’s call to repent.  So instead of offering the thunder judgments as one more opportunity to repent God decides to move toward the final judgment.   John encounters Jesus as a mighty angel (see Exod. 3.2-12; Jud. 6.22; 2 Kgs. 1.3-15; 1 Chron. 21.18 for preincarnate references to Jesus as the angel of the lord).   The angel swears that the time has come for the seventh (and last) trumpet to be sounded and for the mystery of God to be completed.  He recommissions John to take now a message of God’s judgment.  He offers John the scroll to eat.  It is sweet to taste but bitter to eat.  This means the coming salvation for believers and judgment on this age will involve more suffering and persecution for Christians.</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Uncategorized</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bob Harper</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Revelation 8 and 9</title>
		<link>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/04/27/revelation-8-and-9/</link>
		<comments>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/04/27/revelation-8-and-9/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 23:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobharper.org/?p=94</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[n Revelation chapter 8 Jesus opens the last seal provoking one half hour of silence in Heaven.  This is a dramatic pause that heightens the anticipation for what is to come, God’s judgment on the earth.  Revelation chapters 8 &#38; 9 draw heavily on the story of the Exodus.  In both cases God pours out judgments (plagues) on [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>n Revelation chapter 8 Jesus opens the last seal provoking one half hour of silence in Heaven.  This is a dramatic pause that heightens the anticipation for what is to come, God’s judgment on the earth.  Revelation chapters 8 &amp; 9 draw heavily on the story of the Exodus.  In both cases God pours out judgments (plagues) on the earth.  In both cases the objects of the judgment only harden their hearts.  And in both cases the people of God are in the midst of the plagues but protected from them by God.   The first four plagues involve God sending destruction upon the environment.  The fifth and sixth are two successive waves of demonic assault.  It’s like God is giving the people what they have really been asking for, freedom from Him.  They didn’t bargain on that including direct demonic attack.  The images John uses at this point are based on what would give a first century Roman nightmares and not on 21<sup>st</sup> century weaponry.  I argued earlier that the so-called “seal judgments” are ongoing difficulties.  John ties them to Jesus breaking of the seals on the scroll to communicate that God is ultimately in control.  Also, these are problems that characterize every era as Jesus advances His kingdom and moves toward the Second Coming.  I think it also makes sense that the judgments in Revelation 8 &amp; 9 have a certain timeless quality about them.  In other words, John is not describing 6 specific and separate events here.  Rather he is describing the ongoing judgment of God which He uses through the eras to offer repentance to people.  The worst is yet to come!  Regardless a first century reader would see the Roman Empire as the object of the judgment in these chapters and would read (or listen to) them in anticipation that God would soon act.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/04/27/revelation-8-and-9/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="http://www.bobharper.org/podpress_trac/feed/94/0/Rev_8and9.mp3" length="47013971" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>0:48:58</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>n Revelation chapter 8 Jesus opens the last seal provoking one half hour of silence in Heaven.  This is a dramatic pause that heightens the anticipation for what is to come, God’s judgment on the earth.  Revelation chapters 8 &#38; 9 draw heavily on[...]</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>n Revelation chapter 8 Jesus opens the last seal provoking one half hour of silence in Heaven.  This is a dramatic pause that heightens the anticipation for what is to come, God’s judgment on the earth.  Revelation chapters 8 &#38; 9 draw heavily on the story of the Exodus.  In both cases God pours out judgments (plagues) on the earth.  In both cases the objects of the judgment only harden their hearts.  And in both cases the people of God are in the midst of the plagues but protected from them by God.   The first four plagues involve God sending destruction upon the environment.  The fifth and sixth are two successive waves of demonic assault.  It’s like God is giving the people what they have really been asking for, freedom from Him.  They didn’t bargain on that including direct demonic attack.  The images John uses at this point are based on what would give a first century Roman nightmares and not on 21st century weaponry.  I argued earlier that the so-called “seal judgments” are ongoing difficulties.  John ties them to Jesus breaking of the seals on the scroll to communicate that God is ultimately in control.  Also, these are problems that characterize every era as Jesus advances His kingdom and moves toward the Second Coming.  I think it also makes sense that the judgments in Revelation 8 &#38; 9 have a certain timeless quality about them.  In other words, John is not describing 6 specific and separate events here.  Rather he is describing the ongoing judgment of God which He uses through the eras to offer repentance to people.  The worst is yet to come!  Regardless a first century reader would see the Roman Empire as the object of the judgment in these chapters and would read (or listen to) them in anticipation that God would soon act.
&#160;</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Uncategorized</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bob Harper</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Revelation 6 and 7</title>
		<link>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/04/20/revelation-6-and-7/</link>
		<comments>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/04/20/revelation-6-and-7/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 13:37:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bob]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobharper.org/?p=89</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In Revelation 6 the Lamb begins to open the scroll by breaking the seals on it.  And as each seals is broken something bad happens or is released.  These events are not the contents of the scroll but signs that accompany the breaking of the seals.   The first four seals are accompanied by four separate [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In Revelation 6 the Lamb begins to open the scroll by breaking the seals on it.  And as each seals is broken something bad happens or is released.  These events are not the contents of the scroll but signs that accompany the breaking of the seals.   The first four seals are accompanied by four separate horsemen, each of a different color.  The first rider is white and carries a bow.  He is a conqueror bent on conquest.   He represents “wars and rumors of wars.”  The second horseman is red and he carries a sword.  He is to take peace from the earth and turn people on each other.  He represents “nation turning against nation and kingdom against kingdom.”  The third horseman is black and he brings economic hardship.  The last horseman is pale like a corpse and brings death and Hades with him.  When the fifth seal is broken John sees the souls of the martyrs under the altar.  These five things occur in every age and are not the beginning of God’s judgment.  They are the reality of life in a corrupt age.  John wants his listeners to know that these things are not beyond God’s control.  At the breaking of the sixth seal all the powerful people on the earth, along with the slaves and the powerless try to hide under the rocks.  They know that the Day of the Lord has come.   This is an example of the ”looping” chronology of the Book of Revelation.  John tells us things about the future and then loops back to the present.  Then he loops into the past before jumping into the future again.  I believe this throne room scene follows Jesus ascension to Heaven.  In that sense it is past.  Yet the events that accompany the first five seals are always present on the earth.  And the breaking of the sixth seal takes us far into the future.  Before the seventh seal is broken there is an interlude.  This is Revelation 7.  In it John sees two visions of the church.  The first 8 verses speak of the 144,000 servants of God who are sealed in their foreheads.  144,000 is a number that represents completed humanity, humankind in its fullness.  John sorts them by the twelve tribes of Israel.  It is an unusual list because Joseph is included, and there is no tribe of Joseph.   Levi is included, although this tribe is usually left off because they did not receive an inheritance of land within Israel.  Dan and Ephraim are omitted.   Many scholars believe the names on the list are less important than the list itself as representative of the fullness of humanity.  Then John sees a multitude to great to count made up of every tribe, tongue, nation, etc.  One of the elders asks him if he knows who they are.  The question seems rhetorical because he quickly answers, “These are those who came out of the great tribulation.  They washed their robes in the blood of the Lamb.”  They will now always be with the Lamb.   The first century believers believed a time of trouble would precede Jesus’ second coming.   It was a time of “great tribulation” and during it they were participating in the suffering of the Messiah.  Further, they felt they were in that time.  You can see hints of this in the NT (i.e., Col. 1.24; 2 Cor. 1.5a; Phil. 3.10, etc.).  So these are the people of all ages and people groups who become followers of the Lamb.  In these two images, then, John has seen the fullness of the church.  The interlude comes to an end in 8.1 as the seventh seal is broken and heaven falls silent for one half hour.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/04/20/revelation-6-and-7/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="http://www.bobharper.org/podpress_trac/feed/89/0/Revelation_6and7.mp3" length="84892842" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>0:44:13</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>In Revelation 6 the Lamb begins to open the scroll by breaking the seals on it.  And as each seals is broken something bad happens or is released.  These events are not the contents of the scroll but signs that accompany the breaking of the seals.  [...]</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>In Revelation 6 the Lamb begins to open the scroll by breaking the seals on it.  And as each seals is broken something bad happens or is released.  These events are not the contents of the scroll but signs that accompany the breaking of the seals.   The first four seals are accompanied by four separate horsemen, each of a different color.  The first rider is white and carries a bow.  He is a conqueror bent on conquest.   He represents “wars and rumors of wars.”  The second horseman is red and he carries a sword.  He is to take peace from the earth and turn people on each other.  He represents “nation turning against nation and kingdom against kingdom.”  The third horseman is black and he brings economic hardship.  The last horseman is pale like a corpse and brings death and Hades with him.  When the fifth seal is broken John sees the souls of the martyrs under the altar.  These five things occur in every age and are not the beginning of God’s judgment.  They are the reality of life in a corrupt age.  John wants his listeners to know that these things are not beyond God’s control.  At the breaking of the sixth seal all the powerful people on the earth, along with the slaves and the powerless try to hide under the rocks.  They know that the Day of the Lord has come.   This is an example of the ”looping” chronology of the Book of Revelation.  John tells us things about the future and then loops back to the present.  Then he loops into the past before jumping into the future again.  I believe this throne room scene follows Jesus ascension to Heaven.  In that sense it is past.  Yet the events that accompany the first five seals are always present on the earth.  And the breaking of the sixth seal takes us far into the future.  Before the seventh seal is broken there is an interlude.  This is Revelation 7.  In it John sees two visions of the church.  The first 8 verses speak of the 144,000 servants of God who are sealed in their foreheads.  144,000 is a number that represents completed humanity, humankind in its fullness.  John sorts them by the twelve tribes of Israel.  It is an unusual list because Joseph is included, and there is no tribe of Joseph.   Levi is included, although this tribe is usually left off because they did not receive an inheritance of land within Israel.  Dan and Ephraim are omitted.   Many scholars believe the names on the list are less important than the list itself as representative of the fullness of humanity.  Then John sees a multitude to great to count made up of every tribe, tongue, nation, etc.  One of the elders asks him if he knows who they are.  The question seems rhetorical because he quickly answers, “These are those who came out of the great tribulation.  They washed their robes in the blood of the Lamb.”  They will now always be with the Lamb.   The first century believers believed a time of trouble would precede Jesus’ second coming.   It was a time of “great tribulation” and during it they were participating in the suffering of the Messiah.  Further, they felt they were in that time.  You can see hints of this in the NT (i.e., Col. 1.24; 2 Cor. 1.5a; Phil. 3.10, etc.).  So these are the people of all ages and people groups who become followers of the Lamb.  In these two images, then, John has seen the fullness of the church.  The interlude comes to an end in 8.1 as the seventh seal is broken and heaven falls silent for one half hour.
&#160;</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Uncategorized</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bob Harper</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Revelation 4 and 5</title>
		<link>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/04/20/revelation-4-and-5/</link>
		<comments>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/04/20/revelation-4-and-5/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 13:37:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bob]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobharper.org/?p=85</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In Revelation 4 the scene changes and John is brought up through a door to see God’s throne room.  It is a scene of incredible power and purity.  God reigns in majesty and glory as well as in wrath and judgment.  Yet this is tempered by His mercy.  His royal court surrounds him.  It consists [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In Revelation 4 the scene changes and John is brought up through a door to see God’s throne room.  It is a scene of incredible power and purity.  God reigns in majesty and glory as well as in wrath and judgment.  Yet this is tempered by His mercy.  His royal court surrounds him.  It consists of 24 heavenly angelic beings and 4 “living creatures.”  They worship Him continually.  Thunder and lightning, symbolic of imminent and powerful action, explode from the throne.  The seven spirits of God, or the Holy Spirit, are before the Father on the throne.  In Revelation 5 John notices that the Father is holding a scroll in his right hand of authority.  It is written on both sides and sealed with seven seals.  What is it?  Scholars have offered various answers including the Lamb’s Book of Life, the Old Testament, and more.  The best answer is, given the context and where Revelation goes from here, that the scroll contains God’s will and purpose for the creation and is at the same time a deed of inheritance.  This means someone needs to take this scroll and open it for God’s plan to be successful.  John weeps at this point and it is a deep, mournful weeping.  He knows that there is no one worthy enough to open it.  The word “worthy” carries the idea of sufficient more than it carries the idea of purity or morality.  In other words no one is sufficiently able to open the scroll and see God’s purposes fulfilled.  Then one of the elders points out that Lion of the tribe of Judah, the root of David has triumphed.  These terms represent the patriarchs and the kingdom of Israel.  The one called by them is the fulfillment of both.  John looks for what will surely be a strong individual and sees a lamb, as if it had been sacrificed.  He is the worthy one.  He takes the scroll and the praise in the throne room turns from focusing on the Father to focusing on the Son for His redemptive act.  Significantly the Holy Spirit, who is before the Father in chapter 4, is on the Son in chapter 5.  John clearly wants to communicate a Trinitarian theology to us.  In these two chapters, then, we see the powerful and mighty God who is able to overthrow Caesar but who conquers by means of sacrifice.  The first century believers certainly resonated with this message as they considered their own weakness before the Empire.  Their God, who is Almighty, conquers by means of sacrifice.  They will need this to endure.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/04/20/revelation-4-and-5/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="http://www.bobharper.org/podpress_trac/feed/85/0/Revelation_4and5.mp3" length="59650615" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>0:31:04</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>In Revelation 4 the scene changes and John is brought up through a door to see God’s throne room.  It is a scene of incredible power and purity.  God reigns in majesty and glory as well as in wrath and judgment.  Yet this is tempered by His mercy.  [...]</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>In Revelation 4 the scene changes and John is brought up through a door to see God’s throne room.  It is a scene of incredible power and purity.  God reigns in majesty and glory as well as in wrath and judgment.  Yet this is tempered by His mercy.  His royal court surrounds him.  It consists of 24 heavenly angelic beings and 4 “living creatures.”  They worship Him continually.  Thunder and lightning, symbolic of imminent and powerful action, explode from the throne.  The seven spirits of God, or the Holy Spirit, are before the Father on the throne.  In Revelation 5 John notices that the Father is holding a scroll in his right hand of authority.  It is written on both sides and sealed with seven seals.  What is it?  Scholars have offered various answers including the Lamb’s Book of Life, the Old Testament, and more.  The best answer is, given the context and where Revelation goes from here, that the scroll contains God’s will and purpose for the creation and is at the same time a deed of inheritance.  This means someone needs to take this scroll and open it for God’s plan to be successful.  John weeps at this point and it is a deep, mournful weeping.  He knows that there is no one worthy enough to open it.  The word “worthy” carries the idea of sufficient more than it carries the idea of purity or morality.  In other words no one is sufficiently able to open the scroll and see God’s purposes fulfilled.  Then one of the elders points out that Lion of the tribe of Judah, the root of David has triumphed.  These terms represent the patriarchs and the kingdom of Israel.  The one called by them is the fulfillment of both.  John looks for what will surely be a strong individual and sees a lamb, as if it had been sacrificed.  He is the worthy one.  He takes the scroll and the praise in the throne room turns from focusing on the Father to focusing on the Son for His redemptive act.  Significantly the Holy Spirit, who is before the Father in chapter 4, is on the Son in chapter 5.  John clearly wants to communicate a Trinitarian theology to us.  In these two chapters, then, we see the powerful and mighty God who is able to overthrow Caesar but who conquers by means of sacrifice.  The first century believers certainly resonated with this message as they considered their own weakness before the Empire.  Their God, who is Almighty, conquers by means of sacrifice.  They will need this to endure.
&#160;</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Uncategorized</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bob Harper</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Second Coming of Jesus, Part Three</title>
		<link>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/03/23/the-second-coming-of-jesus-part-three/</link>
		<comments>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/03/23/the-second-coming-of-jesus-part-three/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2011 14:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bob]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobharper.org/?p=80</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This message is part three of a three part series on the Second Coming of Jesus as taught in 1st and 2nd Thessalonians.  It deals with 2nd Thessalonians 2.1-12.  We tend to come to the Bible looking for certainty.  We want to absolutely know God, what it means to belong to Him, etc.  And the [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This message is part three of a three part series on the Second Coming of Jesus as taught in 1<sup>st</sup> and 2<sup>nd</sup> Thessalonians.  It deals with 2<sup>nd</sup> Thessalonians 2.1-12.  We tend to come to the Bible looking for certainty.  We want to absolutely know God, what it means to belong to Him, etc.  And the Bible provides certain answers to many of our questions.  At the same time some passages are more obscure like the one discussed in the audio file below this post.  It primarily deals with the figure known popularly as “the anti-christ.”  It is helpful to know some things about 2<sup>nd </sup>Temple Judaism to understand what Paul teaches about this person.  2<sup>nd</sup> Temple Judaism is the period between Israel’s return from exile in Babylon up to the destruction of the “2<sup>nd</sup>” Temple by the Romans in 70 AD.  This period in Israel’s history is one of longing.  They long for God to completely fulfill the promises He made to them while they were in Babylon.  As they wait they look over their ancient texts (at this point this includes the Pentateuch and most but not all of the books in our current Old Testament between Joshua and Ezekiel) and they begin to see things in a new light.  This is when the teaching of the Messiah gains prominence.  The Day of the Lord becomes a major theme.  This is also a period of turmoil as various world empires succeed each other and dominant many people including the Jews.    One military-political leader outlaws Judaism and sacrifices a pig on the altar in the Temple.  This person, and his act, is the basis for the New Testament idea of the “lawless one” who is now being restrained.  In my view the lawless one will rise from within the church and is now being restrained by the preaching of the Gospel.  In this message I also detail the other options available.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/03/23/the-second-coming-of-jesus-part-three/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="http://www.bobharper.org/podpress_trac/feed/80/0/The-Second-Coming-of-Jesus-III.mp3" length="18378628" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>0:38:17</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>This message is part three of a three part series on the Second Coming of Jesus as taught in 1st and 2nd Thessalonians.  It deals with 2nd Thessalonians 2.1-12.  We tend to come to the Bible looking for certainty.  We want to absolutely know God, wh[...]</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>This message is part three of a three part series on the Second Coming of Jesus as taught in 1st and 2nd Thessalonians.  It deals with 2nd Thessalonians 2.1-12.  We tend to come to the Bible looking for certainty.  We want to absolutely know God, what it means to belong to Him, etc.  And the Bible provides certain answers to many of our questions.  At the same time some passages are more obscure like the one discussed in the audio file below this post.  It primarily deals with the figure known popularly as “the anti-christ.”  It is helpful to know some things about 2nd Temple Judaism to understand what Paul teaches about this person.  2nd Temple Judaism is the period between Israel’s return from exile in Babylon up to the destruction of the “2nd” Temple by the Romans in 70 AD.  This period in Israel’s history is one of longing.  They long for God to completely fulfill the promises He made to them while they were in Babylon.  As they wait they look over their ancient texts (at this point this includes the Pentateuch and most but not all of the books in our current Old Testament between Joshua and Ezekiel) and they begin to see things in a new light.  This is when the teaching of the Messiah gains prominence.  The Day of the Lord becomes a major theme.  This is also a period of turmoil as various world empires succeed each other and dominant many people including the Jews.    One military-political leader outlaws Judaism and sacrifices a pig on the altar in the Temple.  This person, and his act, is the basis for the New Testament idea of the “lawless one” who is now being restrained.  In my view the lawless one will rise from within the church and is now being restrained by the preaching of the Gospel.  In this message I also detail the other options available.
&#160;</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Uncategorized</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bob Harper</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Second Coming of Jesus, Part Two</title>
		<link>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/03/23/the-second-coming-of-jesus-part-two/</link>
		<comments>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/03/23/the-second-coming-of-jesus-part-two/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2011 14:33:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bob]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobharper.org/?p=78</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This message is part two of a three part series on the Second Coming of Jesus as taught in 1st and 2nd Thessalonians.  It deals with 1 Thessalonians 5.1-11. Recently a man named Harold Camping broadcast the news that Jesus would return May 21, 2011.  According to CNN.com, “He has dissected scripture and crunched his [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This message is part two of a three part series on the Second Coming of Jesus as taught in 1<sup>st</sup> and 2<sup>nd</sup> Thessalonians.  It deals with 1 Thessalonians 5.1-11. Recently a man named Harold Camping broadcast the news that Jesus would return May 21, 2011.  According to CNN.com, “He has dissected scripture and crunched his biblical numbers to come up with the fateful dates. He rattles off mathematical explanations of how he did this work, throwing out Bible verses and calculations that leave an outsider&#8217;s head spinning…. But Camping also happens to be the man who once said September 6, 1994, would be the big day.”  Camping was wrong in 1994 and he will be wrong again in 2011.  Paul told the Thessalonians that “the day of the Lord will come like a thief in the night.”  His point was, don’t waste your time trying to read the tea leaves of the times (or the supposed math hidden in the Bible) and live as “children of the light and children of the day.”  They were to do this in the midst of a dark age while God worked His transformation within them.  When Jesus returns He will establish God’s kingdom on the earth and those who follow him will rule and reign with him.  In this present “evil age” God is working the power of the resurrection which He will complete when Jesus returns.  This message is about what God is doing now, while we live in this present age and wait for the not yet, the full realization of the Kingdom of God.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/03/23/the-second-coming-of-jesus-part-two/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="http://www.bobharper.org/podpress_trac/feed/78/0/The-Second-Coming-of-Jesus-II.mp3" length="16421534" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>0:34:12</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>This message is part two of a three part series on the Second Coming of Jesus as taught in 1st and 2nd Thessalonians.  It deals with 1 Thessalonians 5.1-11. Recently a man named Harold Camping broadcast the news that Jesus would return May 21, 2011.[...]</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>This message is part two of a three part series on the Second Coming of Jesus as taught in 1st and 2nd Thessalonians.  It deals with 1 Thessalonians 5.1-11. Recently a man named Harold Camping broadcast the news that Jesus would return May 21, 2011.  According to CNN.com, “He has dissected scripture and crunched his biblical numbers to come up with the fateful dates. He rattles off mathematical explanations of how he did this work, throwing out Bible verses and calculations that leave an outsider&#8217;s head spinning…. But Camping also happens to be the man who once said September 6, 1994, would be the big day.”  Camping was wrong in 1994 and he will be wrong again in 2011.  Paul told the Thessalonians that “the day of the Lord will come like a thief in the night.”  His point was, don’t waste your time trying to read the tea leaves of the times (or the supposed math hidden in the Bible) and live as “children of the light and children of the day.”  They were to do this in the midst of a dark age while God worked His transformation within them.  When Jesus returns He will establish God’s kingdom on the earth and those who follow him will rule and reign with him.  In this present “evil age” God is working the power of the resurrection which He will complete when Jesus returns.  This message is about what God is doing now, while we live in this present age and wait for the not yet, the full realization of the Kingdom of God.
&#160;</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Uncategorized</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bob Harper</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Second Coming of Jesus, Part One</title>
		<link>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/03/23/the-second-coming-of-jesus-part-one/</link>
		<comments>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/03/23/the-second-coming-of-jesus-part-one/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2011 14:32:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bob]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobharper.org/?p=76</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The audio file below this post is part one of a three part series on the Second Coming of Jesus as taught in 1st and 2nd Thessalonians. It deals with 1 Thessalonians 4.13-18.  The second coming of Jesus is a well known teaching in 21st century.  It is one of the distinctive things about Evangelical [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The audio file below this post is part one of a three part series on the Second Coming of Jesus as taught in 1<sup>st</sup> and 2<sup>nd</sup> Thessalonians. It deals with 1 Thessalonians 4.13-18.  The second coming of Jesus is a well known teaching in 21<sup>st</sup> century.  It is one of the distinctive things about Evangelical Christianity and virtually every Christian tradition teaches something about it.  Even most unbelievers know that Christians believe that Jesus will return perhaps soon.  And it is widely understood to be an escape from trouble.  Jesus will return and the Christians will depart for Heaven with him just before all hell breaks out on earth.  The Great Tribulation!   The first Christians did not see Jesus return as an escape from trouble.  Rather, they saw it as the culmination of trouble that they assumed they were already in the middle of, a trouble that would turn the page to close this age and open the one to come.  They saw it as the ultimate act of salvation and judgment.  Whenever God saves He also judges and vice-versa.  The Second Coming will be the culmination of His salvation and of His judgment and the realization of His Kingdom on the earth.  It is clear in the New Testament that the early Christians, especially Paul believed that Jesus would return soon, that they would see it.  Paul certainly said that.  He taught that it will be a public event, not a secret coming for the church.  We will be welcoming Jesus into His Kingdom on earth where we will rule and reign with Him.  This is the salvation that Jesus brings with Him at His return.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/03/23/the-second-coming-of-jesus-part-one/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="http://www.bobharper.org/podpress_trac/feed/76/0/The-Second-Coming-of-Jesus-I.mp3" length="16603555" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>0:34:35</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>The audio file below this post is part one of a three part series on the Second Coming of Jesus as taught in 1st and 2nd Thessalonians. It deals with 1 Thessalonians 4.13-18.  The second coming of Jesus is a well known teaching in 21st century.  It [...]</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>The audio file below this post is part one of a three part series on the Second Coming of Jesus as taught in 1st and 2nd Thessalonians. It deals with 1 Thessalonians 4.13-18.  The second coming of Jesus is a well known teaching in 21st century.  It is one of the distinctive things about Evangelical Christianity and virtually every Christian tradition teaches something about it.  Even most unbelievers know that Christians believe that Jesus will return perhaps soon.  And it is widely understood to be an escape from trouble.  Jesus will return and the Christians will depart for Heaven with him just before all hell breaks out on earth.  The Great Tribulation!   The first Christians did not see Jesus return as an escape from trouble.  Rather, they saw it as the culmination of trouble that they assumed they were already in the middle of, a trouble that would turn the page to close this age and open the one to come.  They saw it as the ultimate act of salvation and judgment.  Whenever God saves He also judges and vice-versa.  The Second Coming will be the culmination of His salvation and of His judgment and the realization of His Kingdom on the earth.  It is clear in the New Testament that the early Christians, especially Paul believed that Jesus would return soon, that they would see it.  Paul certainly said that.  He taught that it will be a public event, not a secret coming for the church.  We will be welcoming Jesus into His Kingdom on earth where we will rule and reign with Him.  This is the salvation that Jesus brings with Him at His return.
&#160;</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Uncategorized</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bob Harper</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Revelation 2.17-3.22</title>
		<link>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/03/15/revelation-2-17-3-22/</link>
		<comments>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/03/15/revelation-2-17-3-22/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2011 01:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bob]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobharper.org/?p=70</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Contemporary evangelicalism approaches the Gospel from a place of power, of autonomy, and of entitlement.  This impacts the way we understand the Gospel more than we realize.  We ask questions of it that would be unusual to say the least to first century Christians.  We want to know things like “how do I get saved?” [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Contemporary evangelicalism approaches the Gospel from a place of power, of autonomy, and of entitlement.  This impacts the way we understand the Gospel more than we realize.  We ask questions of it that would be unusual to say the least to first century Christians.  We want to know things like “how do I get saved?” and “how do I get God to answer my prayers.”  The first Christians were powerless, weak, and marginalized.  They were kept from the power centers of their society and so heard the Gospel as a call to be faithful and to endure in a world in rebellion to their God, and therefore potentially hostile to them.  They had to navigate a culture in which idolatry was obvious but also powerful enough to ruin or possibly eliminate one’s life.  In our day the idols are powerful but less obvious and, for now at least, lack the power to eliminate our lives.  In this study of Revelation 2.18-3.22 we look at the last four churches in Asia: Thyatira, Sardis, Philadelphia, and Laodicea.  Each one of them developed a different answer to the dilemma of how much of the prevailing culture should be assimilated and how much should be avoided.  It is helpful to examine their experiences and answers to this dilemma to be able to respond to the idols of our age.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/03/15/revelation-2-17-3-22/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="http://www.bobharper.org/podpress_trac/feed/70/0/Revelation2.18-3.22.mp3" length="49505247" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>0:51:34</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>Contemporary evangelicalism approaches the Gospel from a place of power, of autonomy, and of entitlement.  This impacts the way we understand the Gospel more than we realize.  We ask questions of it that would be unusual to say the least to first ce[...]</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Contemporary evangelicalism approaches the Gospel from a place of power, of autonomy, and of entitlement.  This impacts the way we understand the Gospel more than we realize.  We ask questions of it that would be unusual to say the least to first century Christians.  We want to know things like “how do I get saved?” and “how do I get God to answer my prayers.”  The first Christians were powerless, weak, and marginalized.  They were kept from the power centers of their society and so heard the Gospel as a call to be faithful and to endure in a world in rebellion to their God, and therefore potentially hostile to them.  They had to navigate a culture in which idolatry was obvious but also powerful enough to ruin or possibly eliminate one’s life.  In our day the idols are powerful but less obvious and, for now at least, lack the power to eliminate our lives.  In this study of Revelation 2.18-3.22 we look at the last four churches in Asia: Thyatira, Sardis, Philadelphia, and Laodicea.  Each one of them developed a different answer to the dilemma of how much of the prevailing culture should be assimilated and how much should be avoided.  It is helpful to examine their experiences and answers to this dilemma to be able to respond to the idols of our age.</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Uncategorized</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bob Harper</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Revelation Chapter Two</title>
		<link>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/03/08/revelation-chapter-two/</link>
		<comments>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/03/08/revelation-chapter-two/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 04:42:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bob]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobharper.org/?p=60</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In Chapter Two of the Book of Revelation Jesus address three of “the seven churches” of Asia: Ephesus, Smyrna, and Thyatira.  These were actual churches in the first century and John seems to have had a relationship with them.  They were each contending with a problem which we also find in the contemporary church.  Ephesus [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In Chapter Two of the Book of Revelation Jesus address three of “the seven churches” of Asia: Ephesus, Smyrna, and Thyatira.  These were actual churches in the first century and John seems to have had a relationship with them.  They were each contending with a problem which we also find in the contemporary church.  Ephesus was the doctrinally pure church who moved away from their love for God and each other.  Granted they were “right” about the truth but wrong about the heart of the matter.  Jesus’ word to them is a stern warning.  Today we see many “high tension” churches that draw firm boundaries around the truth, as they understand it.   At the same time they are loveless toward others.  Can they really love God (1 John 4.7)? This type of church is easy to caricature and that faulty picture defines Christianity to the outside world.  Smyrna was the small church facing persecution.  Its problem came from Jews who exposed them to the authorities as people who refused to worship the emperor.  The Jews themselves were legally free from having to worship the emperor.  They saw it as idolatry as did the Christians.  As long as the Romans perceived the Christians to be basically Jews it was no problem.  But it seems that the Jews in Smyrna made it a point to tell the Romans that the Christians were not Jews and that they refused to offer a sacrifice to the Emperor.  Consequently, Jesus tells them, they can look forward to a season of imprisonment and martyrdom.  Jesus’ message to them is comforting.  We see this type of church, the persecuted church, throughout church history and in many places today.   The third church addressed in this chapter is the church of Pergamum.  This church had a problem opposite to that of Ephesus.  Here prophets were encouraging people to embrace the culture, and likely, pagan worship (including immorality) with it.  Pergamum did stand strong in the face of persecution but lacked the necessary regard for the truth.  Jesus’ message to them is a warning that he will judge them according to the sword in his mouth, the Word of God, unless they repent.  And we see many churches of this type in the world today as well.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/03/08/revelation-chapter-two/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="http://www.bobharper.org/podpress_trac/feed/60/0/Revelation-Chapter-2.mp3" length="72634199" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>1:15:40</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>In Chapter Two of the Book of Revelation Jesus address three of “the seven churches” of Asia: Ephesus, Smyrna, and Thyatira.  These were actual churches in the first century and John seems to have had a relationship with them.  They were each conten[...]</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>In Chapter Two of the Book of Revelation Jesus address three of “the seven churches” of Asia: Ephesus, Smyrna, and Thyatira.  These were actual churches in the first century and John seems to have had a relationship with them.  They were each contending with a problem which we also find in the contemporary church.  Ephesus was the doctrinally pure church who moved away from their love for God and each other.  Granted they were “right” about the truth but wrong about the heart of the matter.  Jesus’ word to them is a stern warning.  Today we see many “high tension” churches that draw firm boundaries around the truth, as they understand it.   At the same time they are loveless toward others.  Can they really love God (1 John 4.7)? This type of church is easy to caricature and that faulty picture defines Christianity to the outside world.  Smyrna was the small church facing persecution.  Its problem came from Jews who exposed them to the authorities as people who refused to worship the emperor.  The Jews themselves were legally free from having to worship the emperor.  They saw it as idolatry as did the Christians.  As long as the Romans perceived the Christians to be basically Jews it was no problem.  But it seems that the Jews in Smyrna made it a point to tell the Romans that the Christians were not Jews and that they refused to offer a sacrifice to the Emperor.  Consequently, Jesus tells them, they can look forward to a season of imprisonment and martyrdom.  Jesus’ message to them is comforting.  We see this type of church, the persecuted church, throughout church history and in many places today.   The third church addressed in this chapter is the church of Pergamum.  This church had a problem opposite to that of Ephesus.  Here prophets were encouraging people to embrace the culture, and likely, pagan worship (including immorality) with it.  Pergamum did stand strong in the face of persecution but lacked the necessary regard for the truth.  Jesus’ message to them is a warning that he will judge them according to the sword in his mouth, the Word of God, unless they repent.  And we see many churches of this type in the world today as well.
&#160;</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Uncategorized</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bob Harper</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Revelation Chapter One</title>
		<link>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/03/02/revelation-chapter-one/</link>
		<comments>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/03/02/revelation-chapter-one/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2011 12:14:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bob]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobharper.org/?p=49</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In chapter one of the Book of Revelation John seems to be saying the visions in it are about to happen.  It is the revelation of what &#8220;must soon take place.&#8221;  Those who read it out loud and those who listen to it are blessed &#8220;because the time is near.&#8221; John is communicating with urgency [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In chapter one of the Book of Revelation John seems to be saying the visions in it are about to happen.  It is the revelation of what &#8220;must soon take place.&#8221;  Those who read it out loud and those who listen to it are blessed &#8220;because the time is near.&#8221; John is communicating with urgency about the state of the church.  Many contemporary readers pick up the anticipation John intended with these phrases but misunderstand his overall meaning.  In this message I talk about some of the things that shaped the anticipation a first century reader brought to the book and the details of the vision of Christ found in it.   This vision sets the stage for the next two chapters.</p>
<p>UPDATE: New audio has been uploaded.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/03/02/revelation-chapter-one/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="http://www.bobharper.org/podpress_trac/feed/49/0/Revelation-Chapter-One-rerecord.mp3" length="38660041" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>0:40:16</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>In chapter one of the Book of Revelation John seems to be saying the visions in it are about to happen.  It is the revelation of what &#8220;must soon take place.&#8221;  Those who read it out loud and those who listen to it are blessed &#8220;becau[...]</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>In chapter one of the Book of Revelation John seems to be saying the visions in it are about to happen.  It is the revelation of what &#8220;must soon take place.&#8221;  Those who read it out loud and those who listen to it are blessed &#8220;because the time is near.&#8221; John is communicating with urgency about the state of the church.  Many contemporary readers pick up the anticipation John intended with these phrases but misunderstand his overall meaning.  In this message I talk about some of the things that shaped the anticipation a first century reader brought to the book and the details of the vision of Christ found in it.   This vision sets the stage for the next two chapters.
UPDATE: New audio has been uploaded.</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Uncategorized</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bob Harper</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Revelation Introduction</title>
		<link>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/02/28/revelation-introduction/</link>
		<comments>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/02/28/revelation-introduction/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 02:40:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bob]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobharper.org/?p=42</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Many people read the Book of Revelation in a way similar to how one might read Nostradamus.  They comb its phrases and images for details about the events leading up to Jesus&#8217; second coming assuming it is full of end time secrets.  In my mind this is faulty for more than one reason.  For one [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Many people read the Book of Revelation in a way similar to how one  might read Nostradamus.  They comb its phrases and images for details  about the events leading up to Jesus&#8217; second coming assuming it is full  of end time secrets.  In my mind this is faulty for more than one  reason.  For one thing, why would God give a message that was dark and  incomprehensible to His people who were struggling with persecution that  they could not possibly understand since it was about events that would  unfold over 2000 years later?  The answer is He didn&#8217;t.  He  communicated a message through John that the people who first received  it understood.  It meant something for them and it means something for  us.  The better we understand what it meant for them the better we will  understand what it means for us.  This message is a discussion of  several background issues and provides a fair amount of historical  details.  Like the title says, it is an introduction to the Book of  Revelation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.bobharper.org/2011/02/28/revelation-introduction/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="http://www.bobharper.org/podpress_trac/feed/42/0/Revalation_Introduction.mp3" length="41151842" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>0:42:52</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>Many people read the Book of Revelation in a way similar to how one  might read Nostradamus.  They comb its phrases and images for details  about the events leading up to Jesus&#8217; second coming assuming it is full  of end time secrets.  In my mi[...]</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Many people read the Book of Revelation in a way similar to how one  might read Nostradamus.  They comb its phrases and images for details  about the events leading up to Jesus&#8217; second coming assuming it is full  of end time secrets.  In my mind this is faulty for more than one  reason.  For one thing, why would God give a message that was dark and  incomprehensible to His people who were struggling with persecution that  they could not possibly understand since it was about events that would  unfold over 2000 years later?  The answer is He didn&#8217;t.  He  communicated a message through John that the people who first received  it understood.  It meant something for them and it means something for  us.  The better we understand what it meant for them the better we will  understand what it means for us.  This message is a discussion of  several background issues and provides a fair amount of historical  details.  Like the title says, it is an introduction to the Book of  Revelation.</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Uncategorized</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bob Harper</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Rapture?</title>
		<link>http://www.bobharper.org/2010/08/31/the-rapture/</link>
		<comments>http://www.bobharper.org/2010/08/31/the-rapture/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 13:58:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bob]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobharper.org/?p=32</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[One day, like a thief in the night, Jesus will return secretly to rapture Christians off of the earth just in time for God’s wrath to be poured out on the earth.  Really?  Actually Christians have only believed this for about 140 years.  The doctrine of the Rapture is the product of a unique set [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One day, like a thief in the night, Jesus will return secretly to rapture Christians off of the earth just in time for God’s wrath to be poured out on the earth.  Really?  Actually Christians have only believed this for about 140 years.  The doctrine of the Rapture is the product of a unique set of historical circumstances that began in the 19th century.  J N Darby, a very creative Bible teacher, “saw” a secret teaching in the Bible: God is going to take his people out just before unleashing His awful and terrifying wrath on the earth.   Although Darby was British his teaching and his theological system later called “dispensationalism” really took root in America.   It spread thanks to the fact that Americans in this era were literate for the most part but not educated and because the railroad spanned the nation and brought new things and ideas coast to coast.  Also, in the 19<sup>th</sup> century America was ripe for new “secret” ideas and many groups started based on unique (and often heretical) revelations.  Mormonism, Christian Science, Jehovah’s  Witnesses, and Adventistism all began in this era based on exclusive ideas or revelations.  (I am not saying that Seventh Day Adventists are heretics.) The point is Americans were uniquely ready for something new and exciting in their religion and Darby delivered.  In 1909 C.I. Scofield published the first study Bible, the Scofield study Bible.  In it he incorporated Darby’s teaching in the study notes.  The Bible sold coast to coast and was widely read.  Prophecy conferences sprang up and the “movement” gained steam as the fundamentalists adopted dispensationalism which led to new churches and seminaries that fully embraced the Rapture, often as a primary doctrine.  But is it what the Bible teaches?  In 1<sup>st</sup> Thessalonians 4.15-17 says that we will be “caught up” with deceased Christians to “meet the Lord in the air” and that we will be with him forever.   According to many this is the Rapture.  After this Jesus takes all of us to Heaven where we wait out the seven year Great Tribulation before returning to earth with him.  However, a fair reading of the passage shows that it says absolutely nothing about Jesus turning around and going back to Heaven with or without people.  You can’t even imply it.  It simply is not there.  Plus the word for “meet” is a term that refers to a delegation going outside a city to meet a visiting dignitary to welcome him into the city.  In other words Paul is teaching in 1<sup>st</sup> Thessalonians that we will meet the Lord in the air and escort him to earth to take his rightful place as Lord of all.  There is much more that can be said about what the Bible teaches in this passage and other Rapture favorites.  Download the audio file for my full teaching on this subject.  The bottom line is the teaching of the Rapture is not Biblical, looks silly to thinking non-Christians, and has helped too many Christians retreat from the world rather than engage it on His behalf.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.bobharper.org/2010/08/31/the-rapture/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="http://www.bobharper.org/podpress_trac/feed/32/0/20100830_Rapture.mp3" length="60204422" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>1:02:42</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>One day, like a thief in the night, Jesus will return secretly to rapture Christians off of the earth just in time for God’s wrath to be poured out on the earth.  Really?  Actually Christians have only believed this for about 140 years.  The doctrin[...]</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>One day, like a thief in the night, Jesus will return secretly to rapture Christians off of the earth just in time for God’s wrath to be poured out on the earth.  Really?  Actually Christians have only believed this for about 140 years.  The doctrine of the Rapture is the product of a unique set of historical circumstances that began in the 19th century.  J N Darby, a very creative Bible teacher, “saw” a secret teaching in the Bible: God is going to take his people out just before unleashing His awful and terrifying wrath on the earth.   Although Darby was British his teaching and his theological system later called “dispensationalism” really took root in America.   It spread thanks to the fact that Americans in this era were literate for the most part but not educated and because the railroad spanned the nation and brought new things and ideas coast to coast.  Also, in the 19th century America was ripe for new “secret” ideas and many groups started based on unique (and often heretical) revelations.  Mormonism, Christian Science, Jehovah’s  Witnesses, and Adventistism all began in this era based on exclusive ideas or revelations.  (I am not saying that Seventh Day Adventists are heretics.) The point is Americans were uniquely ready for something new and exciting in their religion and Darby delivered.  In 1909 C.I. Scofield published the first study Bible, the Scofield study Bible.  In it he incorporated Darby’s teaching in the study notes.  The Bible sold coast to coast and was widely read.  Prophecy conferences sprang up and the “movement” gained steam as the fundamentalists adopted dispensationalism which led to new churches and seminaries that fully embraced the Rapture, often as a primary doctrine.  But is it what the Bible teaches?  In 1st Thessalonians 4.15-17 says that we will be “caught up” with deceased Christians to “meet the Lord in the air” and that we will be with him forever.   According to many this is the Rapture.  After this Jesus takes all of us to Heaven where we wait out the seven year Great Tribulation before returning to earth with him.  However, a fair reading of the passage shows that it says absolutely nothing about Jesus turning around and going back to Heaven with or without people.  You can’t even imply it.  It simply is not there.  Plus the word for “meet” is a term that refers to a delegation going outside a city to meet a visiting dignitary to welcome him into the city.  In other words Paul is teaching in 1st Thessalonians that we will meet the Lord in the air and escort him to earth to take his rightful place as Lord of all.  There is much more that can be said about what the Bible teaches in this passage and other Rapture favorites.  Download the audio file for my full teaching on this subject.  The bottom line is the teaching of the Rapture is not Biblical, looks silly to thinking non-Christians, and has helped too many Christians retreat from the world rather than engage it on His behalf.</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Uncategorized</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bob Harper</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Olivet Discourse</title>
		<link>http://www.bobharper.org/2010/08/24/the-olivet-discourse/</link>
		<comments>http://www.bobharper.org/2010/08/24/the-olivet-discourse/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2010 13:25:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bob]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobharper.org/?p=24</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Jesus delivered a dark and complex message to his disciples not long before his crucifixion. It contains allusions to beatings, trials, and family violence over the gospel, wars, earthquakes, famines, and disruptions in the spiritual world. We know the message as “the Olivet Discourse.” (Matthew 24, Mark 13, Luke 21) Most people today interpret it [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jesus delivered a dark and complex message to his disciples not long before his crucifixion.  It contains allusions to beatings, trials, and family violence over the gospel, wars, earthquakes, famines, and disruptions in the spiritual world.  We know the message as “the Olivet Discourse.”  (Matthew 24, Mark 13, Luke 21) Most people today interpret it as either a message about the future in which Jesus is describing frightening events yet to come before his return to earth or, as a failed prediction on his part.  Neither viewpoint is right.  Jesus is drawing on an ancient literary genre, apocalyptic, to describe the events that happened in the wake of his death.  The disciples want to know when the Temple (and Jerusalem) will be destroyed and when the current age will end and the age of Jesus’ reign begin.  Jesus tells them exactly how it will happen.  Then he describes what they can expect: trials, beatings, and other kinds of suffering.  The world around them will seem to be in turmoil from war and natural disaster.   Jesus tells them that despite all of that they are to wait, to preach and to endure.  When they see the Temple being desecrated, as it was during the Greek occupation, they are to flee.  At this point in the message Jesus turns to vivid apocalyptic imagery to describe the changing of the age.   He quotes Joel 2 (a passage which has connections and allusions in many places in the New Testament) saying the sun will be darkened and the moon will not give its light.”  He also talks about the Son of Man “coming in clouds.”  He is figuratively (or apocalyptically) explaining that this is the ultimate end of the Temple and its system as the way to connect with God.  After, the only way to connect with God is through Jesus, the Son of Man.  He closes the message with a strong exhortation to his followers to be faithful, to be active in spreading the Gospel, to be enduring.  The bottom line is they are not asking when he will return after “the Great Tribulation” and he is not cryptically answering it for future generations.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.bobharper.org/2010/08/24/the-olivet-discourse/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
			<enclosure url="http://www.bobharper.org/podpress_trac/feed/24/0/8-23-10.mp3" length="77033302" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:duration>1:20:15</itunes:duration>
		<itunes:subtitle>Jesus delivered a dark and complex message to his disciples not long before his crucifixion.  It contains allusions to beatings, trials, and family violence over the gospel, wars, earthquakes, famines, and disruptions in the spiritual world.  We kno[...]</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Jesus delivered a dark and complex message to his disciples not long before his crucifixion.  It contains allusions to beatings, trials, and family violence over the gospel, wars, earthquakes, famines, and disruptions in the spiritual world.  We know the message as “the Olivet Discourse.”  (Matthew 24, Mark 13, Luke 21) Most people today interpret it as either a message about the future in which Jesus is describing frightening events yet to come before his return to earth or, as a failed prediction on his part.  Neither viewpoint is right.  Jesus is drawing on an ancient literary genre, apocalyptic, to describe the events that happened in the wake of his death.  The disciples want to know when the Temple (and Jerusalem) will be destroyed and when the current age will end and the age of Jesus’ reign begin.  Jesus tells them exactly how it will happen.  Then he describes what they can expect: trials, beatings, and other kinds of suffering.  The world around them will seem to be in turmoil from war and natural disaster.   Jesus tells them that despite all of that they are to wait, to preach and to endure.  When they see the Temple being desecrated, as it was during the Greek occupation, they are to flee.  At this point in the message Jesus turns to vivid apocalyptic imagery to describe the changing of the age.   He quotes Joel 2 (a passage which has connections and allusions in many places in the New Testament) saying the sun will be darkened and the moon will not give its light.”  He also talks about the Son of Man “coming in clouds.”  He is figuratively (or apocalyptically) explaining that this is the ultimate end of the Temple and its system as the way to connect with God.  After, the only way to connect with God is through Jesus, the Son of Man.  He closes the message with a strong exhortation to his followers to be faithful, to be active in spreading the Gospel, to be enduring.  The bottom line is they are not asking when he will return after “the Great Tribulation” and he is not cryptically answering it for future generations.</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:keywords>Uncategorized</itunes:keywords>
		<itunes:author>Bob Harper</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
