<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/" xmlns:blogger="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0" version="2.0"><channel><atom:id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2336282388310163194</atom:id><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 07:58:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><title>THE FUN SHOW cactiradio.com</title><description></description><link>http://omgthefunshow.blogspot.com/</link><managingEditor>noreply@blogger.com (omg)</managingEditor><generator>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>40</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>1</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><item><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2336282388310163194.post-6949217650381325838</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 16:40:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2011-08-27T09:40:57.849-07:00</atom:updated><title>The Fun Phone Prank Show - 08/24/2011</title><description>RBCP, Rob, and Staci all get together to do a show on a Wednesday night just so Staci won&#39;t have another show to edit.&amp;nbsp; RBCP plays a song in the background for the entire show just to piss off Staci and everyone in IRC (and probably in tinychat too.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I will do more updates later...have not caught up on podcasts with all that is going on, and with a new job in the evenings I will probably not be doing any live shows for at least 6 weeks.</description><enclosure type='' url='http://www.cactiradio.com/media/tps/thephoneshow.2011-08-24.mp3' length='0'/><link>http://omgthefunshow.blogspot.com/2011/08/fun-phone-prank-show-08242011.html</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (omg)</author><thr:total>0</thr:total></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2336282388310163194.post-6159821283426590223</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2011 18:03:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2011-07-15T11:03:02.393-07:00</atom:updated><title>The FUN Show - Aikison&#39;s Mom.  Also, My Ferret Is Missing.</title><description>The show starts with a call recorded by Aikison. &amp;nbsp;Badfish calls in and makes my show echo so he&#39;s banned from the show. &amp;nbsp;Lots of people call in and ruin the show. &amp;nbsp;I fool everyone by being invisible on skype! &amp;nbsp;haha! &amp;nbsp;Gas stations don&#39;t care about my missing ferret. &amp;nbsp;Jennn gets connected to the show somehow without calling in. &amp;nbsp;That Charlie guy from Hawaii that Carlito calls gets a call from us and isn&#39;t as funny as he is on Madhouse Live. &amp;nbsp;Staci tries to go to bed but no one will let her. &amp;nbsp;Calls keep getting connected to the show from overseas. &amp;nbsp;Aikison fails at beige boxing. &amp;nbsp;Badfish insists that canning is better. &amp;nbsp;Tabachi called Aikison&#39;s mom. &amp;nbsp;Staci gets told to shut the fuck up on her own show -- again. &amp;nbsp;Mona doesn&#39;t answer our calls anymore and Tabachi tells us all about the big PLA meetup at Tyson Square mall on July 20th. &amp;nbsp;Rapeguy is back and some lady with his phone is very confused! &amp;nbsp;Staci needs permission to make calls on her own show. &amp;nbsp;Someone connects the show with an overseas Taxi company (probably Kuraz) and the show gets a little better. Flying taxi idea inspired by Gnnr. &amp;nbsp;We attempt to do a prank call with gregulate but it&#39;s not as funny as we thought so we&#39;ll do in another time and make you suffer through listening to it in the podcast. &amp;nbsp;They&#39;re just really selective prostitutes. &amp;nbsp;Also, Ellerbeck calls in so you should really listen to the end! &amp;nbsp;IT&#39;S AMAZING! &amp;nbsp;I put RBCP&#39;s Waffle House call at the end.</description><enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://www.phonelosers.com/media/funshow/funshow062211.mp3' length='0'/><link>http://omgthefunshow.blogspot.com/2011/07/fun-show-aikisons-mom-also-my-ferret-is.html</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (omg)</author><thr:total>2</thr:total></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2336282388310163194.post-3689904315728055788</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 00:52:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2011-06-21T17:52:10.092-07:00</atom:updated><title>The FUN Show - Untitled</title><description>Aikison and ladiesrapebabies cohost for me. &amp;nbsp;New summer schedule - 1 hour earlier so remember that. &amp;nbsp;We start off calling angry gas&amp;nbsp;station guy who seems to have taken more anger management. &amp;nbsp;My plan is to call him every week until he gets angry. &amp;nbsp;Nick Walters&amp;nbsp;wins a date with me. &amp;nbsp;Tabachi and HBB are meeting at Tyson&#39;s&lt;br /&gt;Corner on July 30th and would like to invite anyone in the PLA to&amp;nbsp;attend as well. &amp;nbsp;We make prank calls using Yelp and openbook but I&amp;nbsp;don&#39;t want to ruin it for you so just listen. &amp;nbsp;Some lady is&amp;nbsp;arguing with someone in a foreign language and that captivates me&amp;nbsp;so you have to listen to that even though it&#39;s boring. &amp;nbsp;At the end&amp;nbsp;I start hating the show so we just talk about nothing. &amp;nbsp;Some guy that we&#39;ve been pranking calls back and refuses to hang up.</description><enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://www.phonelosers.com/media/funshow/funshow061511.mp3' length='0'/><link>http://omgthefunshow.blogspot.com/2011/06/fun-show-untitled.html</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (omg)</author><thr:total>0</thr:total></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2336282388310163194.post-9139471928932690309</guid><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 20:46:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2011-06-09T13:46:44.845-07:00</atom:updated><title>The FUN Show - Voting Fraud</title><description>Aikison and Staci start the show with a call to Angry Gas Station Guy who seems to have taken anger management since our last encounter. &amp;nbsp;Tabachi calls in and hangs up. &amp;nbsp;The BEST ITALIAN RESTAURANT THREE YEARS IN A ROW has terrible Yelp reviews but the restaurant refuses to acknowledge this. &amp;nbsp;They claim that they were voted into the position but Staci is not convinced. &amp;nbsp;They must have rigged the votes. &amp;nbsp;PHRACTAL ISN&#39;T DEAD and he must be the one behind Phoneweiners because he only came back AFTER Harry stopped coming around. &amp;nbsp;Hmmm. &amp;nbsp;So then Aikison calls back the Italian restaurant and somehow threatens the manager enough to get the cops called (that&#39;s sarcasm in case you can&#39;t tell.) &amp;nbsp;Staci can&#39;t get the medication she needs for her period so Aikison tries to help but nobody cares about race (or color) in Hawaii. &amp;nbsp;Phractal used to prank call AOL but they are no longer in business. &amp;nbsp;Byron from last week was supposed to talk to Angry Gas Station guy but he hangs up out of fear. &amp;nbsp;Angry Gas Station Guy finally gets angry! &amp;nbsp;SUCCESS! &amp;nbsp;Staci tries to get a restaurant to deliver but the lady does not know how to drive. &amp;nbsp;Legend is very hungry but no one will serve him food. &amp;nbsp;Rob spams my show with information about his upcoming show called THE PRANK SHOW on Cactiradio on Saturdays. &amp;nbsp;He won&#39;t stop talking about it so I have to hang up because I&#39;m afraid he will steal my ratings. &amp;nbsp;Tully has been listening to the whole show long enough to call and&amp;nbsp;interrupt&amp;nbsp;us from making funny prank calls to complain that we aren&#39;t making funny prank calls. &amp;nbsp;Staci calls back someone she prank called earlier to admit that she was the one responsible. &amp;nbsp;Aikison calls a Vietnamese restaurant and is accused of&amp;nbsp;harassment&amp;nbsp;for asking her to cook some food. &amp;nbsp;Staci and Aikison call back the Italian Restaurant to get a release form but just end up getting in trouble with homeland security, the FBI, and now the FCC for talking dirty and threatening the restaurant manager. &amp;nbsp;My favorite quote: &quot;Lady, get off the line!&quot; &amp;nbsp;After the show is a call made to Staci from the wine store guy so you can hear how she denies having anything to do with any calls made to the store. &amp;nbsp;Time to go...the FBI will be here in a few minutes!</description><enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://www.phonelosers.com/media/funshow/funshow060811.mp3' length='0'/><link>http://omgthefunshow.blogspot.com/2011/06/fun-show-voting-fraud.html</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (omg)</author><thr:total>0</thr:total></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2336282388310163194.post-5441797000091241216</guid><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2011 19:22:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2011-06-08T12:22:26.470-07:00</atom:updated><title>The FUN Show - 06/01/11 - Hotels and Felonies aftershow</title><description>The aftershow begins with Byron calling us back...AGAIN. &amp;nbsp;He wants to get to know Staci. &amp;nbsp;Staci gets abandoned by everyone and tries to call a hotel to get ahold of the speaker of a convention that the lady is afraid to tell me about. &amp;nbsp;She won&#39;t even read the whole pamphlet! &amp;nbsp;Then she tries to follow proper policy so Staci can&#39;t get transferred to a random room! &amp;nbsp;Sudo tries but the lady does not want to ring the wrong room because it&#39;s SO LATE! &amp;nbsp;This lady is obviously not black but Staci is. &amp;nbsp;Some guy calls in and tells us the stream is lagging. &amp;nbsp;Fun show aftershow is over now.</description><enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://www.phonelosers.com/media/funshow/funshow060111aftershow.mp3' length='0'/><link>http://omgthefunshow.blogspot.com/2011/06/fun-show-060111-hotels-and-felonies.html</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (omg)</author><thr:total>2</thr:total></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2336282388310163194.post-7048916845114509216</guid><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2011 19:09:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2011-06-08T12:22:58.927-07:00</atom:updated><title>The FUN Show - 06/01/11 - Hotels and Felonies</title><description>We start off this podcast with part of some prerecorded calls by Aikison and edited by Tabachi. &amp;nbsp;Official name change to Staci makes it number 3. &amp;nbsp;Hotel calls involving an inflatable swimming pool. &amp;nbsp;Sudo, RBCP, and Aikison inform us about felonies. &amp;nbsp;The phonewieners website is DOWN and RBCP is the prime suspect. &amp;nbsp;An unknown caller ruins our show. &amp;nbsp;More talk about the phonewieners. &amp;nbsp;Sudo fails at getting connected to a random hotel room because an employee is actually doing his job and following the rules. &amp;nbsp;RBCP is pushing buttons and hurting Staci&#39;s ears but he won&#39;t admit it. &amp;nbsp;Chimichanga calls in!! &amp;nbsp;We talk to some guys that are obviously high, stupid, or both. &amp;nbsp;They are pretty funny guys! &amp;nbsp;Byron won&#39;t stop harrassing Staci. You can fit 12 people in a hotel room? &amp;nbsp;Well...they are clowns so maybe it&#39;s because you can fit 12 of them in a clown car. &amp;nbsp;Tabachi finally makes it to the show but it&#39;s too late. &amp;nbsp;The show is ending and the outro is too loud so you can&#39;t here what we&#39;re saying. &amp;nbsp;There&#39;s an aftershow but that&#39;s going to be another file...so enjoy this and quit your bitching.</description><enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://www.phonelosers.com/media/funshow/funshow060111.mp3' length='0'/><link>http://omgthefunshow.blogspot.com/2011/06/fun-show-hotels-and-felonies.html</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (omg)</author><thr:total>2</thr:total></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2336282388310163194.post-1792306562401313201</guid><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 02:41:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2011-05-29T19:41:22.788-07:00</atom:updated><title>the FUN show - 05/25/11 - The RBCP Interview!</title><description>Technical issues because I don&#39;t know how to use anything outside of the kitchen.&amp;nbsp; Some topics that were talked about:&amp;nbsp; the toaster crystals, RBCP&#39;s childhood, pranks you might not have ever heard of, and some of RBCP&#39;s deepest thoughts.&amp;nbsp; Also learn about RBCP&#39;s love for boy bands!&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m not going to tell you anything more because you&#39;ll just have to listen to the show!</description><enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://www.phonelosers.com/media/funshow/funshow052511RBCPInterview.mp3' length='0'/><link>http://omgthefunshow.blogspot.com/2011/05/fun-show-052511-rbcp-interview.html</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (omg)</author><thr:total>4</thr:total></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2336282388310163194.post-8200061997950921449</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 03:26:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2011-05-26T12:55:47.878-07:00</atom:updated><title>the FUN show - 05/18/11 - Midget Surgeries</title><description>&lt;span class=&quot;messageBody&quot;&gt;I invite everyone to call in.&amp;nbsp; Lady at apartment complex doesn&#39;t like it that Staci has a fountain running in her apartment and threatens to enter every single apartment to find her.&amp;nbsp; Trevor calls in and so do a few other people.&amp;nbsp; RBCP has a herpes sore.&amp;nbsp; I call a guy that gives us breaking news about an imaginary hurricane in San Diego.&amp;nbsp; LT Matt is hanging out with Samantha on the roof!&amp;nbsp; Francisco gets a call from a midget named Ashley and she tries to get him to get a special surgery.&amp;nbsp; I play music while waiting for him to call back and I play it SO LOUD that you can&#39;t even hear what we&#39;re saying!&amp;nbsp; Chris Chan&#39;s voicemail is funny.&amp;nbsp; We talk about a bunch of stupid stuff and then we call the wrong guy and end up calling someone that has friends with the FBI and CIA!&amp;nbsp; OH NO!&amp;nbsp; Staci tries to get a visa so she can come to America from Alaska.&amp;nbsp; The lady INSISTS that Alaska is already in the United States but she&#39;s DUMB! JENNNFEST!!!!!!!111&amp;nbsp; You can actually hear us over the outro music this time!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phonelosers.com/media/funshow/apartment_ohemgee_dont_flush_it.mp3&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://www.phonelosers.com/media/funshow/funshow051811.mp3' length='0'/><link>http://omgthefunshow.blogspot.com/2011/05/fun-show-051111-midget-surgeries.html</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (omg)</author><thr:total>5</thr:total></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2336282388310163194.post-8487522505494408471</guid><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2011 03:12:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2011-05-16T20:12:01.547-07:00</atom:updated><title>the FUN show - 05/11/11 - I NEED TO WATER MY PLANTS IN FARMVILLE!</title><description>Corwin cohosts and laughs hysterically throughout my whole show over things that aren&#39;t really funny.&amp;nbsp; Someone is selling a cactus saddle and of course I have to call.&amp;nbsp; Also I call an internet provider and they won&#39;t long into facebook for me or hang up on me.&amp;nbsp; His name isn&#39;t ROY.&amp;nbsp; Tyrone makes a special appearance.&amp;nbsp; Rob comes up with some interesting attributes that are needed for a cactus purchase.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;s got fruit to trade like some nuts (nuts are a fruit?) Corwin might get some extra water dick if he takes vitamins.&amp;nbsp; Some lady puts words into her husband&#39;s mouth so I have to set her straight on that.</description><enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://www.phonelosers.com/media/funshow/funshow051111.mp3' length='0'/><link>http://omgthefunshow.blogspot.com/2011/05/fun-show-051111-i-need-to-water-my.html</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (omg)</author><thr:total>0</thr:total></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2336282388310163194.post-5454950258575713046</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:35:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2011-05-09T17:36:13.616-07:00</atom:updated><title>the FUN show - 05/04/11 - The lost show</title><description>&lt;h6 class=&quot;uiStreamMessage&quot; data-ft=&quot;{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;msg&amp;quot;}&quot; style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;messageBody&quot;&gt;The  FUN show file was corrupt so I used the skype recording instead which  starts halfway into the show. The show sucked so I edited most of it out  and used the aftershow as the actual show. It&#39;s a skype recording so you get to  hear behind the scenes flirting with phractal and the outro music at the  end is really low. ENJOY!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phonelosers.com/media/funshow/funshow050411.mp3&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;</description><enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://www.phonelosers.com/media/funshow/funshow050411.mp3' length='0'/><link>http://omgthefunshow.blogspot.com/2011/05/fun-show-050411-lost-show.html</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (omg)</author><thr:total>0</thr:total></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2336282388310163194.post-189788346241135881</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 23:28:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2011-05-02T16:28:18.074-07:00</atom:updated><title>COME PICK YOUR PICTURES UP</title><description>Gnnr wants to cuddle rth!&amp;nbsp; Tips for Defcon planning.&amp;nbsp; Creepy caller.&amp;nbsp; RBCP is one sexy mofo. Talked to Joe the radio show guy Tombstone&#39;s been bugging recently.&amp;nbsp; He gives us dating advice.&amp;nbsp; It starts turning into Oprah so don&#39;t worry, I save the day with inappropriate questions.&amp;nbsp; I call a lady with a short fuse.&amp;nbsp; KATY PERRY SONG!&amp;nbsp; Joe&#39;s answering machine.&amp;nbsp; WALGREENS.&amp;nbsp; We get numbers and then there&#39;s the resulting prank calls =)&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s all you need to know about that.&amp;nbsp; HEY LADY PICK UP YOUR PICTURES ALREADY.</description><enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://www.phonelosers.com/media/funshow/funshow042711.mp3' length='0'/><link>http://omgthefunshow.blogspot.com/2011/05/come-pick-your-pictures-up.html</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (omg)</author><thr:total>0</thr:total></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2336282388310163194.post-1995794996283119097</guid><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 21:07:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2011-04-30T14:07:56.820-07:00</atom:updated><title>No Chinese Food For YOU!  You gave us wrong number!</title><description>Not only do you&amp;nbsp; need to bring ID to pick up your chinese food, but you also have to give them the same number that shows up on caller ID or they won&#39;t even let you order.&amp;nbsp; Don&#39;t you dare even ASK for a chicken eggroll, either.</description><link>http://omgthefunshow.blogspot.com/2011/04/no-chinese-food-for-you-you-gave-us.html</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (omg)</author><thr:total>1</thr:total></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2336282388310163194.post-2601357803629670061</guid><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 21:06:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2011-04-30T14:06:30.177-07:00</atom:updated><title>Soundproof Studios</title><description>We would like soundproof studios and Libby told us just the guy to call.</description><enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://www.phonelosers.com/media/funshow/soundproofstudios.mp3' length='0'/><link>http://omgthefunshow.blogspot.com/2011/04/soundproof-studios.html</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (omg)</author><thr:total>0</thr:total></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2336282388310163194.post-2218535083729153950</guid><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 20:58:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2011-04-30T13:58:48.095-07:00</atom:updated><title>Inappropriate Dentist</title><description>&lt;h6 class=&quot;uiStreamMessage&quot; data-ft=&quot;{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;msg&amp;quot;}&quot; style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;messageBody&quot;&gt;This  is guaranteed to make you laugh no matter how bad of a day you&#39;re  having. I don&#39;t know why this lady didn&#39;t just hang up and instead  decides to let Rob know how little his genitals are. Just when you think  it&#39;s enough, she takes it a step further (and so does Rob)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;</description><enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://www.phonelosers.com/media/funshow/Inappropriatedentist.mp3' length='0'/><link>http://omgthefunshow.blogspot.com/2011/04/inappropriate-dentist.html</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (omg)</author><thr:total>1</thr:total></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2336282388310163194.post-1556768793936743828</guid><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 20:54:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2011-04-30T13:54:54.912-07:00</atom:updated><title>Subway Chaos!</title><description>I knew I forgot to post something yesterday! &lt;br /&gt;Rob gets a whole bunch of Subway restaurants on the line and chaos occurs.</description><enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://www.phonelosers.com/media/funshow/subwaychaos.mp3' length='0'/><link>http://omgthefunshow.blogspot.com/2011/04/subway-chaos.html</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (omg)</author><thr:total>0</thr:total></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2336282388310163194.post-1643056326328100635</guid><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2011-04-29T20:00:21.340-07:00</atom:updated><title>Stupid Walgreens Customer</title><description>During the Phone Show this week, RBCP talked to a lady and accused her son of having disgusting photos at Walgreens, to which she replied that she wasn&#39;t surprised and it sounds like something he would do.&amp;nbsp; After obtaining the guy&#39;s phone number, we called and left a message to call us back with my show&#39;s phone number.&amp;nbsp; Yesterday, he called back and this is what happened.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yes, his e-mail really is hellslave@****.com</description><enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://www.phonelosers.com/media/funshow/stupidwalgreenscustomer.mp3' length='0'/><link>http://omgthefunshow.blogspot.com/2011/04/stupid-walgreens-customer.html</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (omg)</author><thr:total>1</thr:total></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2336282388310163194.post-8908025934679870610</guid><pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2011 01:21:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2011-04-28T18:21:05.395-07:00</atom:updated><title>My short interview with Rappy Mcrapperson!</title><description>Check him out on the youtubez - www.youtube.com/rappymcrapperson&lt;br /&gt;and of course www.rappymcrapperson.com&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The interview got cut short when his phone died, but some great stuff as always with the Rapperson&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;...and that&#39;s it for today!&amp;nbsp; Check the blog tomorrow for a follow-up to the phone show&#39;s episode where the guy&#39;s mother (in law?) agrees with us that her son probably did actually take disgusting photos!</description><enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://www.phonelosers.com/media/funshow/rappyinterview042211.mp3' length='0'/><link>http://omgthefunshow.blogspot.com/2011/04/my-short-interview-with-rappy.html</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (omg)</author><thr:total>0</thr:total></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2336282388310163194.post-2233247261278257281</guid><pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2011 00:16:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2011-04-28T17:16:16.229-07:00</atom:updated><title>Surprise Fun Show! Rude Businesses 04-22-11</title><description>Rob and I go on Yelp and find the rudest businesses.&amp;nbsp; One of them is a place that does alterations and has a very short fuse.&amp;nbsp; ENJOY!</description><enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://www.phonelosers.com/media/funshow/surprisefunshow042211.mp3' length='0'/><link>http://omgthefunshow.blogspot.com/2011/04/surprise-fun-show-rude-businesses-04-22.html</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (omg)</author><thr:total>0</thr:total></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2336282388310163194.post-6526082444473085430</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 19:02:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2011-04-26T12:02:40.448-07:00</atom:updated><title>the FUN show - 04/20/11 - Four Twenty!</title><description>I prank call some people that are selling items for $420 and accuse them of hiding their pot selling business.&amp;nbsp; It doesn&#39;t work out well so some people &quot;from the internet&quot; call in and Aikison continues to spam the show with &quot;420&quot; in a computer voice.&amp;nbsp; Lots of other stuff happens but I&#39;m lazy so I guess you get the general idea.&amp;nbsp; At about 50 minutes in, it gets hilarious when we call foreign taxi guy.&amp;nbsp; He gives Americans some great advice at the end of our show.&amp;nbsp; Included is an aftershow!&amp;nbsp; After the show, there&#39;s a talk with Rappy and his friend Shinobe.&amp;nbsp; I end up getting my heart broken, but the wedding is still on.&amp;nbsp; Phractal, my virtual boyfriend, calls in while I am talking to Rappy and shit gets REAL...</description><enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://www.phonelosers.com/media/funshow/funshow042011.mp3' length='0'/><link>http://omgthefunshow.blogspot.com/2011/04/fun-show-042011-four-twenty.html</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (omg)</author><thr:total>0</thr:total></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2336282388310163194.post-5091473699927496879</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 16:28:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2011-04-26T09:28:56.884-07:00</atom:updated><title>The FUN show - 04/13/11</title><description>MISSING!&amp;nbsp; I will try to get the copy from Aikison.&amp;nbsp; He broadcasted the show for me on this night and co-hosted with me.</description><link>http://omgthefunshow.blogspot.com/2011/04/fun-show-041311.html</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (omg)</author><thr:total>0</thr:total></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2336282388310163194.post-2626245224304739056</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 15:59:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2011-04-26T09:00:54.422-07:00</atom:updated><title>the FUN show - 04/06/2011 - Movie Theatre Confessions</title><description>We call up movie theatres and confess to terrible things!&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s a spin off of the gas station confessions, but equally as funny.&amp;nbsp; Guests include RBCP (who broadcasted the show for me and edited it,) Rob the Hyena, LT Matt, and a failing Corwin.</description><enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://www.phonelosers.com/media/funshow/funshow040611.mp3' length='0'/><link>http://omgthefunshow.blogspot.com/2011/04/fun-show-04062011-dickmites.html</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (omg)</author><thr:total>0</thr:total></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2336282388310163194.post-2915430068576074611</guid><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 17:42:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2011-04-05T10:43:30.031-07:00</atom:updated><title>Highlights of ME from the Fun Phone Fun Phone show on 04/03/11</title><description>These are some prank calls I did on the Fun Phone Phone Fun show this past Sunday. &amp;nbsp;I was calling gas stations and telling them I needed to open a bottle of beer but didn&#39;t know how then confessing to doing terrible things in the store. &amp;nbsp;The employees were trying to catch me, but I wouldn&#39;t give out my info!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you want to listen to the whole show and not just me (but why would you want to do that?!) go download it at&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phonelosers.com/media/tps/thephoneshow.2011-04-03.mp3&quot;&gt;http://www.phonelosers.com/media/tps/thephoneshow.2011-04-03.mp3&lt;/a&gt;</description><enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://www.phonelosers.com/media/funshow/confessionsphoneshow040311.mp3' length='0'/><link>http://omgthefunshow.blogspot.com/2011/04/highlights-of-me-from-fun-phone-fun.html</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (omg)</author><thr:total>0</thr:total></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2336282388310163194.post-3010956602835926711</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 05:02:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2011-04-03T22:02:47.740-07:00</atom:updated><title>The FUN show - 03/30/11</title><description>Rob the Hyena coshosts.&amp;nbsp; This is the one that we prepped a prank call and then...well you&#39;ll see what happens.&amp;nbsp; I didn&#39;t know we were so mainstream!&amp;nbsp; Then we call best buy but I hate it so I cut most of that out.&amp;nbsp; RBCP interviews me about my biege boxing date.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s an aftershow but I&#39;m not posting it yet.</description><enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://www.phonelosers.com/media/funshow/funshow033011.mp3' length='0'/><link>http://omgthefunshow.blogspot.com/2011/04/fun-show-033011.html</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (omg)</author><thr:total>0</thr:total></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2336282388310163194.post-7469701469982179256</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 13:40:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2011-03-31T06:40:35.603-07:00</atom:updated><title>Prayer Warrior</title><description>I call into a prayer line and tell my sad story.&amp;nbsp; Chris Tomkinson calls afterward and she suspects something is awry...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Everyone loves this call and so should you.</description><enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://www.cactiradio.com/media/funshow/warrior.mp3' length='0'/><link>http://omgthefunshow.blogspot.com/2011/03/prayer-warrior.html</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (omg)</author><thr:total>0</thr:total></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2336282388310163194.post-1052306354890725959</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 21:11:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2011-03-30T14:27:56.566-07:00</atom:updated><title>The FUN show - 03/23/11 - Cat Lady!</title><description>I couldn&#39;t open the file containing what actually broadcasted on the stream so you get to hear the skype recording which means there&#39;s a behind the scenes conversation with co-host Aikison for 3 minutes before the show!&amp;nbsp; Phractal calls in talks about actual phreaking stuff but he gets bored with it so we call weather girl.&amp;nbsp; Aikison discusses his dealings with a 14 year old relentless girl who called him over and over.&amp;nbsp; We check on a guy whose voicemail was hacked last week.&amp;nbsp; The outgoing message is still there!&amp;nbsp; Bowling alley prank call failed but it was a good idea...maybe we&#39;ll do it again another time.&amp;nbsp; Snarky&#39;s at it again.&amp;nbsp; Skype problems!&amp;nbsp; Leet fails to be leet.&amp;nbsp; Other stuff.&amp;nbsp; Aikison confesses to a guy&#39;s voicemail.&amp;nbsp; Snarky. TheN uses a phone with a curly cord. Fix nipples. You can&#39;t hack iphones. Chris Chan&#39;s voicemail.&amp;nbsp; Lady has a cat problem but the show ends.&amp;nbsp; You can&#39;t hear the outro music and I don&#39;t care.&amp;nbsp; She calls back after the show ends and is going to the cop shop right now!</description><enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://www.cactiradio.com/media/funshow/funshow032311.mp3' length='0'/><link>http://omgthefunshow.blogspot.com/2011/03/fun-show-032311-cat-lady.html</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (omg)</author><thr:total>0</thr:total></item></channel></rss>